本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译创作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：haloukeiti     鬼瞳1540     吴小堂     gkall     苏也     icanhd
校对：可乐嘻嘻   监制：可乐嘻嘻   后期：鱼子酱
共  犯
天国之门前站着两个人
Two men standing at the Pearly Gates.
其中一个问另一个  "你怎么死的"
The first man says, "How'd you die?"
另一个回答  "我是冻死的
Second says, "I froze to death.
你呢"
How 'bout you?"
另一个人说道
And the, uh, second man says,
"我怀疑...老婆出轨
"Well, I thought my... my wife was being unfaithful to me,
所以我跑回家"  撑住
so I ran all the way home." Come on.
"冲进卧室"
"And burst into the bedroom."
屋里空空荡荡
There's nothin' here.
-"她就..."  -到那边看看
- "She just..." - Look over there.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
要确定幸存的人...
Make sure there's men on...
这边
Here!
我们在这儿
We're here!
先救他
You take him first.
可是  上尉  他就快...
But, captain, he's as good as...
这是命令
That's an order.
中士
Sergeant.
小心  仔细点  下士
Hey, watch it. Careful. Corporal!
小心他的腿
Watch his leg.
两年后
1865年4月14日
为胜利干杯
Victory!
胜利言之尚早  你们觉得呢
Getting a little ahead of ourselves, don't you think?
威尔  李向格兰特投降了  值得干一杯
Will, Lee surrendered to Grant, so have a drink.
弗雷迪  看见他了吗
Freddie, have you seen him yet?
还有大批的叛军逍遥法外
A dozen rebel armies still in the field.
和平还远着呢
I'd say peace is far from in hand.
汉密尔顿  你就爱煽风点火
Hamilton, you could put frost on a fire.
我没看见  不过一半内阁成员都来了
No, I haven't, but half his cabinet's here.
内政部的...
There's Interior...
和邮政局长
and Postmaster.
财政局的
Treasury.
海军部长
Secretary of Navy.
陆军部长哪去了
Where's War?
在那呢
Ooh, there he is.
天哪  能认识他要我干什么都行
God, what I would give to meet him.
怎么了  等等  你要去哪
What? Wait. Where are you going?
你还想不想认识他了
You coming or not?
你是要...你疯了吗
Are you... Are you mad?
没人引荐怎么接近埃德温・斯坦顿
You can't approach Edwin Stanton without an introduction.
真的吗
Really?
弗雷德里克・艾金
Frederick Aiken.
我都去上帝那兜一圈子才找到你
I've been to Creation and back lookin' for you.
参议员  贝克  汉密尔顿
Senator. Uh, Baker, Hamilton,
请允许我介绍这位出众的马里兰州参议员
allow me to introduce the distinguished senator from Maryland,
-勒韦迪・约翰逊先生  -见到你很荣幸  参议员
- Mr. Reverdy Johnson. - Great honor, senator.
先生们  你们为国争光
Gentlemen, you've done this nation proud.
谢谢夸奖  长官
Thank you, sir.
女士们  女士们
Ladies. Ladies,
允许我介绍这两位真正的战斗英雄
may I present two genuine war heroes.
你们相互认识认识吧
Now you all get acquainted
而我要把这位律师介绍给我的一些
while I introduce the counselor to some of my,
受人尊敬的同僚们
uh, esteemed associates.
-女士们  -你好
- Ladies. - Hello.
人来的不少
It's, uh, quite a turnout.
-你好  -很荣幸认识这位可爱的...
- Hello. - It's an honor to meet the lovely...
人人对于胜利趋之若鹜  弗雷迪
Victory is like shit to flies, Freddie.
你怎么来了  埃德  真是个惊喜
Why, Ed, what a delightful surprise.
活着就有惊喜  勒韦迪
Life's full of them, Reverdy.
这位是陆军部长  埃德温・斯坦顿先生
This is our War secretary, Mr. Edwin Stanton.
见到您真是...太荣幸了  长官
Yeah. It's a... it's a very great pleasure, sir.
艾金腹部中了两枪
Mr. Aiken had two horses shot from under him
依然坚持战斗
and never quit the field.
陆军部正需像你一样的忠诚之士
Could use a loyal man like you over at the War Department,
上尉
Captain.
长官
Sir.
从前线回来后  上尉成了一名律师
Captain's back to bein' a lawyer.
该整理下这个国家了  埃德
Time to heal the nation, Ed,
不能再生战事了
not wage more war.
全心全意一如既往  参议员
Pleasure as always, Senator.
-上尉  -长官
- Captain. - Sir.
很抱歉你今晚见不到总统了
I'm sorry you won't be able to meet the president this evening.
他不会出席了吗
Will he not be attending?
比起一屋子军人的房子
It seems Mrs. Lincoln prefers an evening of theater
林肯夫人好像更愿意去剧院
to a room full of soldiers.
什么都行  我什么都能演
Anything. I can play anything.
比如可怜的小瞎子吗
Poor Blind Boy?
那我还真不知道  什么都行...
I don't know that one. Uh, anything...
谢谢你  尼古拉斯
Oh, thank you, Nicholas.
萨拉...天哪  你太美了
Sarah... oh, my God. You look beautiful.
萨拉  见到你很高兴
Sarah, glad to see you.
弗雷德没说你今晚也会来
Fred didn't mention you'd be joining us this evening.
还真像弗雷德会做的事
That sounds like Fred.
什么像弗雷德会做的事
What sounds like Fred?
不是什么值得一提的事
Nothing you need to worry about.
你现在喝了多少瓶了  尼克
How many bottles is that now, Nick?
不是什么值得一提的数目  弗雷德
Uh, nothing you need to worry about, Fred.
去散散步吗
Shall we take a stroll?
你们回来了  太好了
It's good to have you boys back.
能回来真是太好了
It's good to be back.
能回来真是太棒了
It's very good to be back.
没错
Oh, quite right.
有些姑娘和她们的母亲会看...
Some gals and their mothers would look...
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President.
什么事  参议员
Yes, Senator?
很抱歉打扰您  先生
I'm sorry to bother you, sir,
但我需要您对此的授权
but I need your authorization on this.
非要赶现在吗  我有许多客人
Is it really necessary right now? I have so many guests.
恐怕这事更紧要些
I'm afraid it's relatively urgent.
你的眼睛得避开阳光
You have to keep the sun out of your eyes,
直视目标  用力扣动扳机
look straight, pull strong,
计算好距离
calculate the distance,
就能枪枪命中
and you'll hit the mark every time.
-怎么了  -不清楚
- What? - Not sure.
先生
Sir?
是的  我有个给苏厄德部长的包裹
Yes, I have a package for Secretary Seward.
我们是老朋友了  特伦查德先生
We are old friends, Mr. Trenchard,
而且你不用害怕我们
and you needn't be afraid of us.
我才不怕你
I ain't afraid of you,
你们两个加在一起也不怕
both of you together.
再来一杯吗
Want another?
先生
Sir?
斯坦顿部长是个聪明人
Secretary Stanton is a smart man.
有你是陆军部的福气
The War Department would be lucky to have you.
见到他确实很荣幸  可是...
It was an honor to meet the man, but...
我想远离战事
I'm eager to put the war behind me.
你穿军服真的很帅
You do look awfully handsome in your uniform.
估计我又要去习惯你
I suppose I'm going to have to get used to you
身着平头百姓的衣服了
in civilian clothing again.
那你确实有想我吧
So you did miss me?
偶尔吧
On occasion.
我现在没什么财产
Now I've no fortune,
但是我的感情充斥着我
but I am filled over with affection
令我蓄势待发要扑向你
that I am ready to pour over you
正如炖苹果扑在烤猪肉上
like apple sass over roasted pork.
特伦查德先生
Mr. Trenchard!
你在我面前  跟我女儿滔滔不绝起来了
You are addressing my daughter, and in my presence!
没错  只要她想
Yes! I'm offering her my heart
我的心以及我的手都可以奉上
and my hand just as she wants them,
不过心空空  手也空空
with nothing in 'em.
现在我明白了  特伦查德先生
Now, I'm aware, Mr. Trenchard,
你还没学会礼貌这件事...
that you are not used to the manner of polite...
抱歉  不好意...
Pardon me. I'm sor...
见鬼
Shit.
-不  -等等
- Oh, no! - Hold it!
停下  不要
Stop! No!
请不要  别那么做
No, please! Don't!
救命
Help!
来人救命
Somebody help!
救命
Help!
...对那些你所犯的错
...to which you have fallen guilty.
好吧  看就知道你的阴谋了  老姑娘
Well, I guess I know enough to turn you inside out, old gal,
你这个火上浇油的死老家伙...
you sockdologizing old man-trap...
暴君必亡[拉丁语]
Sic semper tyrannis!
这是南方的复仇
The South is avenged!
他要跑了
He's getting away!
拦住他
Stop him!
快点
Come on.
过来  混蛋
Come here, you son of a bitch!
不能...让你跑了
Can't get... let you out of here!
怎么了
What is it?
-少将  -发生什么事了
- Major? - What's happened?
林肯遇刺了
Lincoln's been shot.
-什么  -他中枪了
- What? - He's been shot.
你待在这儿
You stay here.
开门
Open the door.
中士
Sergeant.
让开
Stand aside.
那边
Over there.
马路对面
Across the street.
把路让开
Make way!
请让开
Please, stand aside.
拜托
Please.
往后退  拜托
Move back! Please!
-借过  -让让
- Coming through. - Clear the way!
后退  让开
Back! Stand aside!
你能看见什么吗
Can you see anything?
开门
Open the door!
走那扇门
Try the other door.
换条路
Find another way!
让开
Stand aside.
那边
Over here!
快进来
Come on inside!
退过来  退过来
Back here. Back here.
稳点放他下来
Set him down easy.
医生在哪儿
Where's the doctor?
拿几条毛巾来
Get some towels.
部长先生  等等  先生
Mr. Secretary, wait, sir.
不  我要见他
No. I want to see him.
把路让开
Make way!
别挡路
Out of my way!
让开
Move aside!
出去  让开
Out! Move!
-他在哪  -他在那边  先生
- Where is he? - He's down there, sir.
那里  先生
There, sir.
打扰一下  部长先生
Excuse me, Mr. Secretary.
测测他的脉搏
Take his pulse.
部长先生  是个演员干的
Mr. Secretary, it was the actor,
叫作约翰・威尔科斯・布思
John Wilkes Booth.
肯定吗
Are you certain?
他们跟他一起表演过许多次  非常肯定
They've performed with him many times. They're positive.
我们没做错什么  会没事的
We haven't done anything wrong. It's gonna be all right.
这么精妙的布局不可能是一个人策划的
Well, one man did not orchestrate all of this on his own.
格兰特在哪
Where's Grant?
他在去费城的火车上
He's on a train to Philadelphia.
带他来见我
Bring him to me.
让联邦军指挥官过来
I want the commander of the Union army here.
-快去  -是的  长官
- Move. - Yes, sir.
进入戒备状态  全副武装
Put the forts on alert, all guns manned.
查查内阁大臣
And find out which members
还有谁下落不明
of the Cabinet are still unaccounted for.
长官  我们应该搬到陆军部协助调查
Sir, we should move to the War Department to facilitate operations.
-我不会离开他的  -是的  先生
- I'm not leaving him. - Yes, sir.
该死的叛军
Damn the rebels.
都应该下地狱十八层
Damn them all to hell.
部长先生  先生
Mr. Secretary, sir.
查到几个人  长官
Several names have come up, sir,
包括布思的一位密友
including an intimate of Booth's,
名叫约翰・萨拉特
a John Surratt.
他什么情况
What is known of him?
二十一岁  当地人
21 years old, lives here.
其母经营一家镇上的客栈
His mother runs a boarding house in town.
找到他
Find him.
封锁全城
I want the city closed.
要是有刺客到了
If any of these assassins get
波托马克河南岸或者加拿大
south of the Potomac or up into Canada,
就无迹可寻了
they will never be found.
马上办  长官
Right away, sir.
副总统还想要来拜访以示关注
Also the vice president wishes to pay his respects.
等局势安全了再让他来
When I say it is safe for him to do so.
还有让他别喝酒
And keep him away from the liquor.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
把那个女人带走  别让她再进来了
Take that woman out, and do not let her in again.
星期六早晨  4月15日
林肯总统遭到谋杀  举国震慑  华盛顿
陆军部  华盛顿  1865年4月20
十万美金赏金令
斯坦顿命军队封锁华盛顿
我们走
Let's go.
不是我  不是我
It wasn't me. It wasn't me.
走快点
Move it!
起来  你
Get up, you!
不要
No!
刺客无一漏网
突查萨拉特客栈
共犯玛丽・萨拉特  于客栈被捕
追踪布思的士兵认为其逃向南方
布思
Booth.
击毙布思于谷仓
举国哀悼
火车载林肯遗体穿越美国
百万民众瞻仰亚伯拉罕・林肯
各车站追思者如云
林肯抵达安息之地  伊利诺斯  斯普林菲尔德
那是由法官决定的
That's for the judge to decide.
长官
Sir.
很高兴你现身了  艾金先生
Well, nice of you to show, Mr. Aiken.
很抱歉我迟到了  参议员
I'm sorry for being late, Senator.
你知道共犯的审讯从今天开始吧
You aware the trial of the conspirators begins today?
是的  长官  我还没有被指派辩席
Yes, sir. There's not a seat to be had.
那么  现在你有了
Well, now you have one.
怎么讲  先生
How's that, sir?
我接了其中一件案子
I've taken one of the cases,
我想让你来当助理律师
and I want you to be my second chair.
我以为政府会安排在军事法庭进行
I thought the government was planning a military tribunal.
的确如此  斯坦顿选了九名
Oh, indeed. Stanton has chosen
他信任的联邦军官作为法官
nine of his most loyal officers to be judges, all for Union.
事实上  他选了一名
In fact, he's picked one of
林肯的拥趸作为委员长
Lincoln's pallbearers to head the Commission.
我们走
Uh, let's go.
很抱歉  长官
Uh, I'm sorry, sir.
可能是我没跟上你说的
I might be being a little slow,
但不是陆军部
but won't the War Department
负责起诉吗
be handling the prosecution?
斯坦顿最信任的军法署署长
Stanton's most trusted judge advocate general,
约瑟夫・霍特  为负责人
Joseph Holt, will be in charge.
那我们干什么
Then what are we to do?
为八人中的一个辩护
Defend one of the eight.
为一名刺客辩护吗
Defend one of the assassins?
是刺客嫌疑人  律师
Alleged assassins, counselor.
今天早上我收到一封这位女士的来信
I had a letter from the lady this morning.
她开了一间客栈
She runs a boarding house,
是一名叫作玛丽
a Mrs. Mary...
萨拉特
Surratt?
对  就叫这个
Yes, that's it.
先生  他儿子约翰是布思的得力助手
Sir, her son John was Booth's right hand.
要是他们怀疑她儿子  就该审他
Well, if they suspect her son, they should try him.
要是能抓到他  他们就审了
They would if they could find him,
但是他们已经派了二百五十名特工去找他
but they've got 250 agents out looking for him.
她建了这个老巢用以密谋
She built the nest that hatched this plot.
约翰逊总统如是说
President Johnson said it himself.
我知道这对你来说很难  弗雷迪
Well, I know this goes hard with you, Freddie,
但是...但是他们安排的
but... but what they're plannin',
是一场针对公民的军事审判
which is a military trial of civilians,
是一场暴行
is an atrocity.
不  不是的  她做的才叫暴行
No, no. What she did is an atrocity.
没有无罪的可能
There's no presumption of innocence,
证据无关紧要
no burden of proof,
没有同辈陪审团  也不准上诉
no jury of your peers and no appeal.
很好  你也是林肯的拥趸
All right, you were one of Lincoln's pallbearers, too.
那你怎么能代表她呢
How can you represent her?
她有辩护权  弗雷迪
She's entitled to a defense, Freddie,
所以我要为她辩护
so I shall defend her.
玛丽・E・苏拉特
Mary E. Surratt,
因参与帮助武装叛乱
in aid of the existing armed rebellion against the United States,
你被控招待  窝藏
you are charged with having received, entertained,
救助以及协助约翰・威尔科斯・布思
harbored, concealed, aided and assisted John Wilkes Booth,
约翰・A・萨拉特及其同伙
John A. Surratt and their confederates...
戴维・E・赫罗尔德
David E. Herold...
刘易斯・佩恩
Lewis Payne...
乔治・A・阿泽特
George A. Atzerodt...
迈克尔・劳克兰
Michael O'Laughlen...
埃德蒙・斯潘格勒
Edmund Spangler...
塞缪斯・A・马德
Samuel A. Mudd...
以及塞缪斯・阿诺德
and Samuel Arnold...
密谋刺杀前总统
in traitorous and murderous conspiracy to
亚伯拉罕・林肯
kill then-President Abraham Lincoln,
副总统安德鲁・约翰逊
Vice President Andrew Johnson
以及国务卿威廉・苏厄德的叛国行动
and Secretary of State William Seward.
根据特令211及216
Pursuant to special orders number 211 and 216,
你要如何抗辩
how do you plead?
你怎么说  女士
What say you, madam?
有罪还是无罪
Guilty or not?
我是清白的
I am innocent.
那样的话  由于被告各方都作了
In that case, as each of the defendants
无罪抗辩  我们将要开席
has entered a not-guilty plea, we will begin.
军法官霍特  请开始审讯
Judge Advocate Holt, please proceed.
等一下  法官大人
Just a moment, Your Honor.
什么事  参议员
What is it, Senator?
我...我想提请暂停审讯
I... I wish to request an adjournment.
暂停审讯吗  我们刚刚开始
An adjournment? We just got here.
我的委托人被拘留一个月
My client has been in custody for a month,
昨天才准许与律师联络
wasn't allowed to contact counsel until yesterday.
亨特上将
General Hunter,
延期只会延长全民的哀伤
a delay will only serve to prolong the nation's sorrow.
我博学的同僚
My learned colleague,
你花了四个多星期准备这个案子
you've had over four weeks to prepare your case,
并且得到了陆军部的帮助
no doubt assisted by the entire War Department.
我认为被告有权受到平等对待
I believe the defendant is entitled to equal consideration.
约翰逊参议员
Senator Johnson,
我们的同胞都应该早日平息此痛
our fellow citizens must be permitted to put this tragedy to rest.
尽早将此事处理完毕
The sooner we dispose of this matter,
对大家都有好处
the better... for everyone.
我的委托人除外
Everyone but my client.
霍特法官  请继续
Judge Advocate Holt, please proceed.
这样的话  我请求此案终止
In that case, I move for termination.
终止
Termination?
因为这种审判是违宪的
On the grounds this trial is unconstitutional.
被告也是美国公民
The defendant is a civilian
有权在同辈陪审团前接受公开审判
entitled to a public trial before a jury of her peers.
总检察长已经
The attorney general has
肯定了此次审判程序的合法性
affirmed the legitimacy of this proceeding.
他是不是把最终裁决也定好了呢
Has he furnished a verdict as well?
参议员
Senator.
你要考虑我们内心的伤痛
You will mind the horror which summons us.
当然
Indeed.
我们都对总统之死沉痛万分
We all mourn the loss of our leader,
但哀思之时
but in our grief,
也请大家不要因此作出错误判断
let us not betray our better judgment
成为异端审判的一员
and partake in an inquisition.
异端审判  此话何意
Inquisition? How dare you?
看来我们中有内敌啊
Sounds to me like we have the enemy among us.
马里兰州在战争中就不在我们一方
Maryland not being among our most loyal of states during the war,
州参议员就更应该表明自己的立场
its senator ought to certify his allegiance to this court.
我堂堂司法部长  尽职尽责
I have served this nation as its attorney general.
这还不足以证明我的立场吗
That is certification enough.
不过我们仍需要辩护律师
Nevertheless, we may require counsel
签署这份效忠宣誓
to sign this oath of loyalty
这是国会的规定
as prescribed by Congress.
我也是国会的一员
I am a member of Congress,
是我们组建了军队
the same body that creates armies,
授权军事裁决
authorizes military tribunals
任命像你这样的少将
and makes major generals like you.
我们是由陆军部长埃德温・斯坦顿亲自授权的
Our authorization comes from the War secretary, Edwin Stanton,
并由总统直接下达指令
and by order of the president.
如果我们的开国元勋们奉行暴政
If our founding fathers had desired tyranny to prevail,
那么他们会纵容
the president and his War secretary
总统和战争部长滥用权利
would have been granted such indiscriminate powers,
而事实上  他们起草了宪法
but they drafted a Constitution
用法律禁止了权利滥用
with laws against such powers.
正是为了防止现在这样的情况发生
They did so precisely for times like this.
肃静  肃静
Order! Order! Order!
我真心希望你能帮助我  弗雷迪
I really want you to do this for me, Freddie.
你不会是认真的吧
You're not serious.
委托人被控重罪  岂能儿戏
As serious as the charges against our client.
我  替她辩护
Me? Defend her?
要是我这样的南方老头给她辩护
She doesn't stand a chance
她必输无疑
with an old Southerner like me defending her.
她需要一个像你这样的北方上尉
She needs a Yankee captain like you.
很抱歉  长官  我无能为力
I'm sorry, sir. I... I can't do it.
不  你能行  小伙子
No, you'll do fine, son.
现在他们随心所欲制定规则
Experience matters for nothing
我的经验毫无用武之地
when they're making up the rules as they go along.
而且  政府从没有对女人处以绞刑
Besides, this government has never executed a woman.
他们从未料到会有人  不管是男是女
They've never considered a woman, nor a man for that matter,
能谋杀总统
capable of murdering the president.
先生  我可以找个叛贼来给她辩护
Sir, I can find you a rebel to defend her,
但我自己不能  也不会这样做
but I ca... I won't do it.
要是用南部联邦的辩护律师
There is no court in the Union
全国没有一个法庭
that would fairly judge that
会对那个女人进行公正裁决
woman with a Confederate counsel.
我不会背叛我的国家
I won't betray my country.
也不会背叛为国捐躯的兄弟们
I won't betray my friends who died defending it.
我并不是让你背叛忠心  弗雷迪
I'm not asking you to betray your allegiances, Freddie.
我只是请求你  或者说告诉你
I'm simply askin' you... rather tellin' you...
要遵守律师的职业操守  全力而为
to obey your oath as a... as an attorney and do your job.
他要我替玛丽・萨拉特辩护
He wants me to represent Mary Surratt.
什么
What?
-什么  -是啊
- What? - Yeah.
他不是认真的吧
He can't be serious.
他们都是剧院的演员
They're the actors from the theater.
开门
Open up.
谢谢你
Thank you, soldier.
不客气
That'll be all.
谈话是保密的
This conversation is privileged.
抱歉  先生  这是命令
Sorry, sir. Orders.
约翰逊参议员在哪儿
Where is Senator Johnson?
参议员让我接手你的案子
The senator has instructed me to handle your case.
知道你被指控什么罪名吗
You understand what you've been charged with?
密谋杀害总统
Conspiring to murder the president,
国务卿和副总统
secretary of State and the vice president...
如果罪名成立  你会被处以绞刑
if found guilty, you could hang?
恕我冒昧  贵姓
No disrespect, Mr...
艾金
Aiken.
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken.
你多大了
How many years have you?
二十七
27.
你以前接过这样的案子吗
So you've handled cases like this before?
以前根本就没有这种案子
There's never been a case like this before.
但你替别人辩护过
But you have defended others.
我到底还是没希望啊
They've left nothing to chance.
行了
Very well.
你在H街 541号有一处客栈
You own a boarding house on 541 H Street?
是吗
Is that correct?
是的
Yes.
你在那儿住多久了
How long you been there?
女士
Ma'am?
我对你的了解不过是报纸上的那些
All I know about you is what I read in the papers.
不是恭维
It's not flattering.
一年前  丈夫死后
I moved to Washington a year ago
我带着儿子女儿搬到华盛顿
with my son and daughter after my husband passed.
刺客们是你家的常客
And the assassins were frequent visitors to your home.
是的
Yes.
那你
Well, you... heh.
你都不否认你认识约翰・威尔科斯・布思
You don't even deny having been acquainted
和别的犯人吗
with John Wilkes Booth and the others behind bars?
不  不否认
No, sir, I do not.
我丈夫酗酒而死  艾金先生
My husband died a drunk, Mr. Aiken,
给我留了一屁股债
and left me loads of debt.
我要养活全家
I had to support my family,
所以把房子租给了那些寄宿的
so I rented rooms to boarders.
他们只不过是我的房客
Those men were customers, nothing more.
你就没有考虑过他们的政治立场吗
And you never considered their allegiances?
没有问过
I didn't ask about their allegiances.
你效忠哪一方
What about yours, ma'am?
我是南方人
I am a Southerner.
信天主教
I'm a Catholic
但最重要的  我是个尽责的母亲
and a devoted mother above all else...
不是杀手
but I am no assassin.
你想重获自由  光凭这句保证远远不够
Your freedom is gonna require greater assurances than that.
那你说我应该跟那些将军说些什么
Then you tell me what I should say to those generals.
你得保持沉默
Oh, you can't say a thing.
你不能为自己辩护
You're prohibited from testifying in your own defense.
不过你儿子倒是可以帮你这个忙
Perhaps your son could speak for you.
你知道他藏在哪儿吗
Any idea where he's hiding?
不知道
No, I don't.
那好吧  有人向你解释过这件事吗
All right. Is there anyone who will give your version of events?
你是说事实吗
You mean the truth?
很显然政府
Well, obviously the government
并不相信你说的是事实
believes your version is not the truth.
凭什么
Based on what?
他们不愿公布目击者名单
They're not releasing their list of witnesses
和指控你的证据
or the evidence they'll use against you.
这合法吗
And can they do that?
走这种程序
This kind of proceeding,
都是他们说了算
they can do to you whatever they want.
那还折腾什么
Well, then what difference does it make?
那些将军已经下定论了
Those generals have made up their minds.
从他们看我的眼神就知道
I can tell by the way they look at me.
看你的眼神
The way they look at you?
和你看我的眼神一样
Just the same way you're looking at me.
我得走了
I have to go.
祝你愉快
Good day.
艾金先生  进来后我就没了女儿的消息
Mr. Aiken, I haven't a word from my daughter since I've been here.
你能顺便帮我看望她一下吗
Would you look in on her for me?
我感激不尽
I'd be most grateful.
谢谢
Thank you.
士兵
Soldier.
我是弗雷德里克・艾金  玛丽・萨拉特的律师
Frederick Aiken, lawyer to Mary Surratt.
好极了
It's perfect.
你说什么
Pardon?
安娜・萨拉特吗
Anna Surratt?
我叫弗雷德里克・艾金
My name is Frederick Aiken.
我是你母亲的辩护律师
I'm representing your mother.
什么好极了
What's perfect?
没什么
Uh, nothing.
说说看
No, do tell.
比这更难听的话我都听过
I'm sure I've heard much worse.
我只是在想
Well, I was just thinking that this would be
这是个密谋推翻政府的好地方
the perfect place to conspire to overthrow the government.
不会招人怀疑
No one would ever suspect.
不是吗
Right?
就你一个人吗
You alone here?
是的
Yes.
怎么了  你怕被人看到和我在一起吗
Why? Are you afraid to be seen with me?
你母亲让我来看望你
Your mother asked that I look in on you.
告诉她别担心
Please tell her not to worry,
我也不过是个关在家里的囚犯
since I'm a prisoner in my own house.
你弟弟的房间在哪儿
Where's your brother's room?
二楼左手边
Second floor, on the left.
找到要找的了吗
Did you find what you were looking for?
找到了
Uh, yes.
你弟弟跟L.J. W同住吗
Did your brother share a room with an L.J. W?
路易斯・J・怀克曼
Louis J. Weichmann.
他和我妈亲如母子
He was like a son to my mother.
他会证明我妈是无辜的
He'll swear she's innocent.
他也失踪了吧
I suppose he's disappeared, too.
你参与内战了吗  艾金先生
Did you fight in the war, Mr. Aiken?
杀过我们的人吗
Kill any on our side?
小姐  你有没有什么房客名单
Miss, do you have any documents
或者账本之类的文件
indicating who stayed here or a ledger of accounts?
你想不想让我帮你母亲
Do you want me to help your mother or not?
还藏了什么东西吗
Is there anything else you're concealing?
比如说
Such as?
比如说你弟弟  如果你知道...
Your brother, to start. Look, if you know...
看到是谁扔的吗
Did you see who threw that?
没有  先生
No, sir.
你没伤着吧
Are you hurt?
我没事
I'm fine.
艾金先生  没什么事的话  我先失陪了
Mr. Aiken, if you have no further need of me...
我要买两个
Here. I'll give you two to sell.
你有这个的新款吗
You have the latest on this one?
我拿两个
That, I'll take two.
雪茄  罐子
Cigars! Jars!
相框
Picture frames!
新颖独特  来看看吧  女士
Original, right here, ma'am.
有人要雪茄吗
Who wants a cigar?
刚出炉的坚果
Fresh roasted nuts here.
Fresh roasted nuts.
走开  别挡道
Move along. Mustn't keep it blocked.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
一
Left.
一  二  一
Left, right, left.
-雪茄  -一
- Cigars! - Left...
雪茄
Cigars!
一  一  一
Left. Left. Left.
一  二  一
Left, right, left.
一
Left...
放下枪
Company, arms rest.
-起步走  -枪上肩
- March. - Shoulder arms.
小步跑
Quick step.
一
Left.
一  二  一
Left, right, left.
有机会扳回一城吗
A chance to get it back?
他来了
There he is.
弗雷德
Fred.
汉密尔顿来帮你打下手
Hamilton here has offered to be your second chair.
希望渺茫啊
Oh. Re... Not a chance in hell.
-是吗  你确定  -确定
- No? You sure? - Oh, yeah.
我来拿他的公文包  但我不会...
I'll carry his briefcase, but I'm not...
-萨拉  -弗雷德
- Sarah. - Fred.
你怎么在这儿
Why are you here?
我想知道你在这儿干些什么
I'm trying to understand why you're here.
看来我得祝你好运了
I suppose I should wish you luck.
肃静
Come to order.
安娜怎么样  艾金先生
How is Anna, Mr. Aiken?
她很好
She's fine...
盼着你回家
Looking forward to when you come home.
多谢你这么说  艾金先生
That's very nice of you to say, Mr. Aiken.
霍特法官  能开始了吗
Judge Advocate Holt, will you please proceed?
传唤玛丽・萨拉特一案中
In the matter of Mary Surratt,
第一证人路易斯・怀克曼先生
the prosecution calls as its first witness Mr. Louis Weichmann.
他跟你们不是很亲么
I thought he was like family.
为什么传唤他
Why are they calling him?
把你的右手放在圣经上
Place your right hand on this Bible.
我不知道
I don't know.
你是否发誓说出真相
Do you swear to tell the truth,
毫无保留  不加掩饰的真相
the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
以此让上帝帮助你
so help you, God?
我发誓
I do.
请
Please.
你认识被告玛丽・萨拉特吗
Are you acquainted with the defendant, Mary Surratt?
是的  我认识
Yes. Yes, I am.
他儿子约翰是我在神学院的同学
I attended Divinity College with her son John.
最近  你住在玛丽・萨拉特的客栈里
And until recently, you resided at the boarding house
是吗
owned by Mary Surratt. Is that correct?
是的  先生
That is correct, sir.
这其中有人在她家里出现过吗
Were any of these men ever present in her home?
有的  先生
Yes, sir.
那边的三个
These three over there
去过几次
on several occasions.
证人指认了
Let the record reflect that the witness has identified
赫罗尔德  佩恩和阿泽特三位犯人
the prisoners Herold, Payne and Atzerodt.
是谁请他们来的
And who invited these men?
约翰・萨拉特
John Surratt.
反对
Objection.
Objection?
根本无法证明约翰・萨拉特认识这些人
There's no way to prove that John Surratt
何来邀请之说呢
even knew these men, let alone invited them.
萨拉特无法出庭
Mr. Surratt's absence from this proceeding
是他自己的问题
is Mr. Surratt's problem.
反对无效  继续  霍特先生
Objection overruled. Continue, Mr. Holt.
约翰・威尔科斯・布思是不是约翰・萨拉特的常客
Was John Wilkes Booth also a frequent guest of John Surratt?
没错  但萨拉特全家都很喜欢他
Indeed, but all the Surratts adored him...
约翰  他姐姐安娜还有他们的母亲
John, his sister Anna and their mother, too.
那么布思先生有没有
And were there ever meetings
参加客栈的密谋
held at the boarding house involving Mr. Booth?
参加了多次  有的时候一开就是两三个小时
Many, sometimes lasting two, three hours
而且都是关门秘密进行
and always in secret, behind closed doors.
那你有没有看到
And did you ever see Mary Surratt
玛丽・萨拉特反对这些会议
object to these, uh, meetings?
没有  先生
No, sir.
或者不允许这些人参加
Or to the presence of those men?
不  她没有
No, she did not.
-谢谢  -她似乎很欢迎他们
- Thank you. - She appeared to welcome them.
谢谢  无需补充  怀克曼先生
Thank you. That'll be all, Mr. Weichmann.
你说这些秘密会议一般开多久
How long did you say these secret meetings lasted?
至少两三个小时
At least two, three hours.
你计时的吗
You were timing them?
如果你计了时
Eh, if you were timing them,
那我猜想  这些秘密会议
I suppose these secret meetings
对你来说  不是秘密了吧
were not, in fact, kept secret from you.
我只是知道有这么回事  先生
I knew about them, sir,
但我不知道会议内容是什么
but I had no knowledge of what they were about.
是不是因为你自己从来不参加
And that is because you never attended any yourself, correct?
正是
Exactly.
为什么呢
Why was that?
我觉得他们可疑
I thought them suspicious.
可疑
Suspicious?
你看  你又不知道会议内容
Well, then, you see, you did know what they were about.
我不知道  先生
No, sir, I did not.
那你怎么会觉得可疑
Then why were your suspicions aroused?
因为我听到了有关叛变的只言片语
By the snatches of rebel conversation
我在门厅里无意中听到的
I overheard in the hallways
而且他们总是窃窃私语
and by their frequent whisperings.
好吧  既然你这么在意
Well, in that case, if it was of such great concern to you,
为什么不把这个疑点
why did you not report your
上报给陆军部的长官们呢
suspicions to your superiors at the War Department?
我报了
I did.
是吗
Excuse me?
我的确上报了
I did reveal my suspicions.
还有幸结交陆军部的格里森上尉
I made a confidant of Captain Gleason in the War Department.
艾金先生  如果没有什么
Mr. Aiken, if there's nothing else...
律师先生  你问完了吗
Counselor, will that be all?
完了
Uh, yes.
不
Uh, no.
不  我还有一些要问的
No. No, I do have something else.
告诉我  怀克曼先生  告诉我们大家
Tell me, Mr. Weichmann. Tell us all.
-你有没有去过里士满  -反对
- You ever been in Richmond? - Objection.
我只是想知道证人
I merely wish to know if the witness
有没有去过南部联邦的首都
has ever visited the capital of the Confederacy.
我不记得了
I don't recall.
这张车票收据或者可以唤起你的记忆
Then perhaps this train receipt will refresh your memory.
上面显示目的地是里士满
It indicates passage to Richmond,
还有签有你名字的首字母
and it has your initials on it.
是的
Yes.
的确如此
That's right.
我打算战后在那里继续学习神学
I considered continuing my divinity studies there after the war.
我想成为一名牧师
I plan on becoming a priest.
很好
That's very nice.
你记得吗  怀克曼先生
Do you recall, Mr. Weichmann,
你打算进入里士满的哪所学校呢
at which institute in Richmond you were thinking of enrolling?
学校的名字吗
The name?
是的  怀克曼先生  学校名字
Yes, Mr. Weichmann, the name.
-当地没有这类的学校  -反对
- There is no academy of the kind... - Objection.
在里士满有吗  怀克曼先生
...in Richmond, is there, Mr. Weichmann?
事实上  你去里士满肯能是为了
In fact, perhaps you visited Richmond...
反对  上将
Objection, General.
完全为了其他目的
...for another purpose entirely.
反对有效
Objection sustained.
你在主管叛军囚犯的上将
You worked for the general
的手下工作  是吧
in charge of rebel prisoners, did you not?
是的
Yes.
又如何
So?
像你这样出色的职员
Perhaps a distinguished
可能知道一些消息
clerk like yourself knew certain information.
哪方面的消息
What sort of information?
让南部首都叛党
Information that might have been of divine interest
十分感兴趣的消息
to certain rebels within the capital of the Confederacy.
反对  上将
Objection, General.
证人不是审判席的被告
The witness is not on trial here.
他本应受审
Well, he ought to be!
反对有效
Objection sustained.
证人不是来受审的
The witness is not on trial.
长官  我只是在求证证人的可信度
Sir, I am merely trying to establish the witness' credibility
准确来讲  是证明此人不可信
or rather the lack of credibility of this man.
艾金先生  你在给证人入罪
Mr. Aiken, you are incriminating the witness.
这算入罪吗  长官
Incriminating? Sir,
路易斯・怀克曼和约翰・萨拉特住同一个房间
Louis Weichmann shared a room with John Surratt.
我手头上有一张车票表明他去过里士满
I have a ticket that puts him in Richmond.
我认为有足够的理由相信
I think it reasonable to assume
他对此次刺杀总统的阴谋的了解
that he knows more about this plot to assassinate our president
比他告诉我们的要多
than he supposedly reported.
艾金先生的猜测缺乏实质根据
What Mr. Aiken thinks is entirely immaterial.
辩方律师  如果你没有相关的问题
Counselor, unless you have something more relevant to ask,
证人就退下了
the witness will step down.
没有问题了
No.
没有相关的问题了
No, I have nothing more... relevant to ask.
你绝对不能问一个
You never... you never ask a question
你不知道答案的问题
you don't know the answer to.
我明白
I know. I know.
你怎么知道怀克曼
How... How did you know Weichmann
在里士满的问题上撒谎呢  弗雷德
was lying about Richmond, Fred?
-我不知道  -你居然不知道
- I didn't. - You didn't?
那你是赌了两次啊
S-so you gambled twice?
你怎么通过律师考试的
How did you pass the bar?
但是这招管用
Well, well, it worked.
弗雷德让怀克曼看上去跟其他人一样有罪
I mean, Fred made Weichmann look as guilty as the others.
-好极了  -那是
- It was perfect. - You're right.
这就是问题所在
And that's the problem.
他们都貌似有罪
They all look guilty.
弗雷迪  抱歉
Freddie, I'm sorry.
首先参议员把你当事人当作包袱一样扔掉
First the senator drops your client like a load,
接着所有密谋的会议
and then with all these secret meetings taking place,
或者她知道其内情
either she knew what was going on...
还是她该死的"被知道"呢
Or she damn well should have known.
参议员
Senator?
在里面
In here.
我认为她跟布思一样有罪
I think she's as guilty as Booth.
我又怎能为她辩护呢
How could I possibly defend her?
你跟审判委员会一样  预设了她是有罪的
You assume that she's guilty, like the Commission.
你没有任何证据和证明
You don't have any proof.
无论有没有证据
Proof or no,
都不会改变她做过的事情
don't give a damn what happens to her.
我可以告诉你
I tell you what.
如果你可以证明她有罪
If you can prove that she's guilty,
你就不用再管这案子
you can take yourself off the case.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, sir.
你觉得事情会很简单吗
You think it'll be that easy?
我明白
I know it.
抱歉  神父
Pardon me, Father.
我想跟犯人谈一谈
I wish to confer with the prisoner.
如果你不介意  我想单独谈一谈
Alone, if you don't mind.
没问题  玛丽
It's... It's quite all right, Mary.
我也正要走了
I... I must be going anyway.
好的  谢谢你来看我  神父
All right. Well, thank you for visiting, Father.
再见
I'll see you soon.
你的话让我很安慰
Your words were most comforting.
主与你同在
The Lord's with you.
她绝食
She's refusing to eat.
我已经尽量说服她这样是没好处的
I've tried to convince her to no avail.
可能你可以帮她
Perhaps you could help her.
求你鉴察我  知道我的心思
"Search me, and know my heart.
旧约圣经  诗篇
试炼我  知道我的意念
Try me, and know my thoughts.
看在我里面有什么恶行没有
And see if there be any wicked way in me."
主洞悉罪恶
"The Lord knows the way of the wicked.
旧约圣经  箴言篇
罪恶将消失
And the way of the wicked will perish."
你熟读箴言  年轻人
You know your Proverbs, young man.
我父亲是牧师
My father was a minister.
小时候他教我的
He taught them to me as a child.
那么  你想知道什么
So, what is it you wish to know?
为什么布思和他的同党是你家的常客呢
Why Booth and his associates were constants in your home.
我开客栈的  艾金先生
I ran a boarding house, Mr. Aiken.
招待房客有何不妥
Forgive me if I chose to fill it with boarders.
我查过客栈的入住登记  太太
I checked your registry, ma'am.
并没有显示布思曾经入住
There's no record Booth ever stayed at your home.
事实上
No, the fact is he stayed
他每次来华盛顿都住在国家广场附近
at the National whenever he came to Washington,
那为什么布思会在你家呢
so why was Booth in your home?
估计是我儿子请他来的  他们是朋友
I suppose my son invited him. They were friends.
像布思这样的著名演员
Famous actor like Booth?
会跟你儿子这么熟吗
Engaging your son out of friendship?
艾金先生  我儿子是跟你一样的年轻人
Mr. Aiken, my son is no less a gentleman than you
善于结交朋友
and very capable of forming acquaintances in society.
我问过你家的所有熟人
I've... I've read all about your family's acquaintances, ma'am,
关于你的丈夫对南方邦联事业的贡献
about how your late husband contributed to the Confederate cause
以及你的乖儿子约翰尼
and about your Gentleman Johnny.
他怎么了
What about him?
他通过在北方联邦边界
He made quite a sum as a
传送叛军秘密情报赚了一大笔
courier carrying rebel secrets across Union lines.
我很清楚你们一家子的底细
Oh, I'm well aware of what your family's capable of,
萨拉特太太
Mrs. Surratt,
我知道你没说真话
so I know you're not telling me the truth.
说说看我隐瞒什么了
Well, then you know what I do not.
你为战败沮丧
You were despondent over losing the war,
你想必竭尽所能挽救南方邦联
and you would have done anything you could to save the Confederacy,
包括利用你的儿子
including using your own son John.
老实说  艾金先生
Honestly, Mr. Aiken.
你安排与布思见面
So you arranged a meeting with Booth,
估计他会因为你儿子作为一个情报员
figuring he'd befriend your son because of what he knew,
所知道的消息而去帮助他
what expert couriers do know.
那会是什么情报呢
And what might that be?
逃出本城的最佳路线
The best escape routes out of town.
那个晚上你儿子应该是负责
Your son was supposed to lead
带其他人逃跑的  对吧
the others to freedom that night, wasn't he?
否则怎么可能只有他一个逃得掉呢
Except he was the only one that got away.
那晚我儿子在加拿大
My son was in Canada that day.
你能证明吗
Can you prove that?
四月十四日  我收到一封信
I received a letter on April 14,
正是刺杀当日
same day as the assassination,
那封信是从蒙特利尔寄来的
sent from Montreal.
现在信在哪里
Where is this letter?
我不知道
I don't know.
算了
I'm done,
我没法继续为你的谎言辩护
done defending your lies.
怨恨使你盲目  艾金先生
You're so blind with hatred, Mr. Aiken,
让你看不见真相
you can't even see the truth.
是的  我儿子憎恨北方  我们所有人都是
Yes, my son hated the North. We all did.
除了对你们的怨恨
How can a Southerner feel anything
南方人还能有什么感想
anything but bitterness toward your side?
但是我儿子没有合谋刺杀你们的总统
But my son did not conspire to kill your president.
他只是合谋绑架他
He conspired to kidnap him.
好  他来了
All right, here he comes.
准备好马匹
Ready your mount.
萨拉特  布思哪里去了
Surratt, where the hell's Booth?
他会来的
He'll be here.
好  稳住了
All right, steady.
等一下
Wait!
他不来了
He's not coming!
林肯改变了计划
Lincoln's changed his plans.
-什么  -他还在城里
- What? - He's still in town.
他在国家广场发表演讲
He just gave a speech at the National.
安娜  回到楼上去
Anna, back upstairs.
马车里的是谁
Who was in the carriage?
这不重要  问题是他不在马车里
Doesn't matter. What matters is he wasn't in the carriage.
你应该知道的
You should have known.
武器怎么办
What about the weapons?
我们要把武器藏起来
We need to hide these weapons.
可以放在劳埃德家里
We can take them to Lloyd's.
交给我吧
I'll take 'em.
你这是自绝死路
You'd shoot your own foot off.
我能办好
I said I'd do it.
不要推我
Don't push me.
够了
Enough!
就是你们这样的笨蛋让我们吃败仗的
Fools like you are the reason we can lose this fight.
约翰尼・萨拉特  我有话要跟你说
Johnny Surratt, I'd like a word with you, please.
约翰尼  你妈喊你呢
Well, answer, Johnny. Your mama's callin'.
他们计划用林肯作为人质
They planned on ransoming Lincoln in exchange
交换监狱里的南方邦联士兵
for all the Confederate soldiers in your prisons.
为什么你不向当局报告这件事
Why didn't you report them to the authorities?
因为他们其中一个是我儿子
Because one of them was my son.
所以现在不是绑架了
So rather than kidnap him,
你儿子成了刺杀总统的帮凶
your son helped murder the president instead.
不
No.
他们几乎抓了副总统和国务卿
They nearly got the vice president and the secretary of State.
不是这样的  不是我的约翰尼做的
No, it's not true. It's not my Johnny.
拜托  太太
Damn it, ma'am,
你刚刚才说他是布思的得力助手
you just said he was Booth's right hand.
我儿子不是凶手  艾金先生
My son is not a murderer, Mr. Aiken.
那好
All right, then.
对着它发誓
Swear to it.
马上可以吃晚饭了
Supper will be ready shortly.
约翰
John?
我得走了  妈
Can't stay, mama.
我要马上出城
I have to leave town straightaway.
什么事情这么急
What's so pressing?
不用担心
Nothing that need worry you.
只是去处理一些棉花投资生意  没什么
Just some cotton speculatin'. That's all.
别骗我  儿子
Don't sport with me, son.
不说清楚别指望踏出家门一步
You're not steppin' outside this house.
别把我当小孩
Don't talk to me like I'm a child!
里士满快要沦陷  必须有所行动
Richmond's falling. Something must be done.
约翰尼  我也知道里士满的局势
Johnny, I'm aware of the news from Richmond,
也感到很痛心
and it pains me terribly.
晚饭做好了
Supper's ready.
怎么回事
Wh-what is it?
我要离开本城
I'm leaving town.
不  你不能走
No, you're not leaving town.
我必须走
Yes, I am.
我只剩你和安娜两个亲人了
You and Anna are the only family I've got left,
如果我让你出去干傻事
and I'll be damned if I let
我会受到报应的
you go out there and do something else foolish.
-傻事  -约翰尼
- Foolish? - Johnny...
我正在做的这事
What I'm fightin' for is
比我们任何一个人都重要
far more important than any of us.
你的家人才是最重要的
Your family is more important than anything.
这是你的责任
That is your responsibility!
我们家的男人都死了
All of our men are buried underground right now.
-战争结束了  -你错了
- The war is over. - Oh, you're wrong about that.
没有事情需要你去战斗了
There is nothing left for you to do.
战争远没结束
The war is far from over,
还有很多事情需要我去做
and there's still plenty I can do.
-约翰尼  求你了  -放开我  妈
- Johnny, please. - Unhand me, Mother.
放开我  妈
Unhand me, Mother.
约翰
John!
妈
Mother.
约翰  你还来不来
John, are you coming or not?
约翰尼  求你了
Johnny, please.
如果这不值得我去战斗  那什么值得
If this cause ain't worth fightin' for, then what is?
那是不是你最后一次见到你儿子
So that was the last time you saw your son?
是的
Yes.
在刺杀之前不到两个礼拜
Less than two weeks before the assassination?
是
Yes.
看  你承认
So then, you see, you admit
你儿子合谋刺杀林肯总统了
that your son conspired to kill President Lincoln.
我不知道
I don't know.
但愿上帝能帮你
May God help you.
说真的  艾金先生  我不知道
Honestly, Mr. Aiken, I don't know.
主  我真的不知道
Lord, I pray not.
我所知道的就是我没做过
All I know is that I did not.
我发誓
I swear.
萨拉特小姐
Miss Surratt.
你必须老老实实告诉我...
You have to tell me exactly...
我妈怎样了
How is my mother?
她还撑得住  你必须告诉我
She's managing. You have to tell me
这里到底发生了什么事情
exactly what happened here.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你知道你们的朋友路易斯・怀克曼
Do you know that Louis Weichmann, uh, your friend,
指证你的母亲
testified against your mother
你之前还告诉我他像你妈的儿子一样
after you told me he was like a son to her?
到底怎么回事
What went on here?
我为什么要相信你
Why should I trust you?
因为你母亲已经把所有事情告诉我了
Because your mother told me everything.
她讲了约翰的事情
She told me about John.
还有绑架林肯总统的阴谋
She told me about the plot to kidnap President Lincoln.
安娜  你有没有尝试阻止他
Anna, did you try and stop him?
为什么觉得我要那样做
How was I supposed to do that?
因为你是他姐姐
'Cause you're his older sister.
你不知道我弟弟多么顽固
You don't know how stubborn my brother can be.
好  你弟弟有合谋刺杀总统吗
All right. Did your brother conspire to kill the president?
我弟弟在刺杀之前数周就已经出城了
My brother left town weeks before the assassination.
这证明不了什么  他离开客栈的当晚
It proves nothing. Look, the night he left the boarding house...
我已经把知道的全告诉你了
I've said all I will.
萨拉特小姐
Miss Surratt, I'm trying...
我在尽力帮你们
I'm trying to help.
以给我弟弟入罪的方式吗
By condemning my brother?
艾金先生  我妈绝不同意这样做
Mr. Aiken, my mother would never allow that,
我也不同意
and neither would I.
好  看  你见识过怀克曼了
Oh. All right. All right, look, you knew about Weichmann.
如果你知道谁可能会被检控作为证人传召
If you know any potential witnesses the prosecution might call
或者一些对她不利的证据
or what evidence they'll use against her,
务必告诉我
you must tell me.
你会帮我吗
Will you help me?
让我们跟进一些
Let us proceed with events
总统被刺杀后发生的事情
following the assassination of President Lincoln.
四月十七日晚上
On the night of April 17,
你的职责是什么  史密斯少校
what were your duties, Major Smith?
我负责追捕约翰・萨拉特
I was charged with finding John Surratt,
我们正在搜查房子
and we were searching the house.
少校  我找到这些
Major, I found these.
在他们家女儿的房间找到的
They were here in the daughter's bedroom.
史密斯少校  请读出这里题铭的内容
Major Smith, please read aloud what's inscribed here.
暴君必死
"Sic semper tyrannis."
拉丁文  据说出自刺杀凯撒
可以翻译一下吗
Could you translate?
当然  暴君必死
Of course. "Thus always for tyrants."
这句话你很熟悉吗
Are those words familiar to you?
确实
Indeed.
布思刺杀总统之后喊出了这句话
Booth yelled them after he cut down our president.
事发后三天  你在她女儿房间
You found the same three days later
在杀手照片的旁边
in her daughter's bedroom next to a photograph
看到这句话
of the assassin himself.
像是暗语
Like a shrine, sir.
请继续
Please continue.
反对
Uh, objection.
暴君必死  是佛吉尼亚州的格言
Sic semper tyrannis is the state motto of Virginia.
很难证明是布思的暗语
It hardly constitutes proof of a shrine to Booth.
不需要进一步的证据  艾金先生
No further proof is needed, Mr. Aiken.
继续  霍特先生
Proceed, Mr. Holt.
继续  史密斯少校
Continue, Major Smith.
正当我准备把
As I was fixing to take
萨拉特一家带回总部问话
the Surratts to headquarters for questioning,
这时有人敲门
there was a knock at the door.
还好吧  太太
You all right, ma'am?
恐怕我找错门了
I... I must be mistaken.
等一等
Wait a minute.
你想找谁
Whom do you wish to see?
萨拉特太太
Uh, Mrs. Surratt.
这里是她家  让他进来
This is her place. Bring him in.
她约了你吗
Is she expecting you?
她让我帮她挖一条排水沟
She sent for me, asked me to dig a gutter for her.
要在晚上这个时候挖吗
At this time of night?
明早  我来问下确切时间
In the morning. I just wanted to know what time.
把萨拉特太太带过来
Bring Mrs. Surratt in here.
太太  你雇了这位先生为你挖水沟吗
Ma'am, did you hire this man to dig a gutter for you?
没有  长官
No, sir.
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?
不认识  长官
No, sir.
她否定认识的是这个人吗
Is this the man she denies knowing?
不是
No, sir.
她否定认识的是这个人吗
Is this the man she denies knowing?
是的
Yes, sir.
刘易斯・佩恩
Lewis Payne.
就是他  在刺杀国务卿及其亲戚之前
The same man boarded at the Surratts' prior to
去了萨拉特那里
daggering the secretary of State and his kin.
是的
Yes.
谢谢  少校  我没什么要问的了
Thank you, Major. Nothing further.
史密斯少校  你知不知道刘易斯・佩恩
Major Smith, are you aware that Lewis Payne
来到萨拉特客栈时
boarded at the Surratts'
自称是一名
under an alias,
来自巴尔的摩教会的牧师
claiming to be a Baptist minister from Baltimore
名叫伍德
named Wood?
那是萨拉特夫人说的
That's what she claimed.
是吗
She claimed?
我现在要呈交一份证物
I would like to submit
这是萨拉特客栈的
into evidence this ledger of guest accounts
房客入住登记
from the Surratt boarding house.
假如真是这样的话
Supposing, as this evidence
那么根据这件证物
would seem to suggest, that that were the truth...
则可以推测那晚萨拉特夫人
suppose Mrs. Surratt simply failed that night
并没有认出
to recognize Wood the preacher
乔装成挖沟人佩恩的伍德牧师
in the guise of Payne the ditch digger.
他就站在她面前  只有三步之遥
He was standing in full view of her not three paces.
亨特上将  我接手这个案子后发现
General Hunter, since accepting this case,
我的当事人视力存在缺陷
I have come to learn that my client's eyesight is defective.
我这有一份
I have here a sworn affidavit
她医生的起誓证明
from her doctor stating just that.
史密斯少校  当时是夜里  周围漆黑
Major Smith, it was dark. It was nighttime.
玛丽・萨拉特有没有可能
Isn't it possible Mary Surratt simply...
没认出他来
failed to see him?
如果是我  看到一个人打扮成牧师
If I saw a man dressed as a preacher
而两个月后变成一个苦力
and two months later a laborer,
我照样能认出他来
then I would recognize him as the same person.
谢谢  史密斯少校
Thank you, Major Smith.
请简单的回答  是或是不是
A simple yes or no will do.
有没有可能  她就是没有看清
Is it possible she failed to see him properly?
有  我说有这可能
Yes, I suppose it's possible.
我的提问结束了
No further questions.
控方看来除了合理的怀疑之外
The prosecution seems unable to present any proof of guilt
不能出示任何有罪的证明
beyond a reasonable doubt.
有谁能给我拿一份今天的开庭记录
Uh, could somebody bring me the transcript of today's trial?
我大声读给你听吗
Shall I read it aloud to you?
埃德
Oh, Ed.
你那位小朋友现在展开了激烈的辩护
Your young associate is putting up a spirited defense.
让我想起了25年前对簿公堂的某位律师
Reminds me of a certain lawyer I had to face 25 years ago.
他在你的军队里学会了战斗
Ah, he learned to fight in your army.
我给你来一杯
Can I get you a drink?
不  不  我就待一小会儿  勒韦迪
No, no. No, I won't be staying long. Reverdy...
我了解你为这个国家鞠躬尽瘁
You've done as much for this nation as any man I know.
咱俩都是  埃德
Oh. Feeling's mutual, Ed.
你不觉得咱们这两个
Don't you think it's time
老头子是时候该休战了吗
for us two old war horses to call a truce?
只要你停止这场闹剧就行
Not if you insist on staging this travesty.
这项审判对于和平
This trial will do more to keep the peace
比任何纸上的协议  都要来得重要
than any paper treaty could.
你怎么能够就那么确信
Heh. How'd you convince yourself of that?
因为公正  迅速且坚定的判决
Because justice, swift and firm,
会使南部诸州的任何阴谋势力望而却步
will help deter the South from ever conspiring again,
也能使北部的复仇势力失去勇气
as well as discouraging the North from seeking revenge.
那法律的原则该怎么办
What about the rule of law?
我的第一要务就是
My first responsibility is to ensure that
保证这场战争的胜利
this war stays won.
这就是你的方式吗
Oh, and this is how you do it,
通过利用恐惧来达到你的目的
by keeping fear alive as long as you see fit?
看  "斯坦顿警告今后叛党的阴谋"
Look. "Stanton warns of future rebel plots,"
水中下毒
uh, water supplies poisoned, um...
焚烧城市
firebombing cities.
黄热病蔓延整个地区
Uh, yellow fever spreading all over the place.
这已经是一个足够叫人害怕的国家  埃德
This is a frightened country, Ed.
不需要你再来添把手
You don't need to scare us anymore.
那谁能说这种事情不会发生
And who is to say that none of these things could happen?
如此难以想象的事情已经发生了
The unspeakable already has...
我们的总统被暗杀  六十万人死去
Our president assassinated, 600,000 dead.
勒韦迪  世界已经变了
The world has changed, Reverdy.
可放弃宪法绝不是办法
Abandoning the Constitution is not the answer.
你也许更喜欢独自用餐
You may prefer dining alone.
我只是希望你那位小朋友也明白
I just hope your young associate does as well.
如果他逼得太紧了
If he pushes too hard,
那么他要面对的敌人会让他一生难忘
he will make enemies who will not soon forget.
对于这点  你最清楚
On this, you know I'm right.
我来见斯坦顿部长  伙计们
I'm here to see Secretary Stanton, boys.
退下
Stand down.
抱歉  先生
Sorry, sir. Mr. Stanton
没有预约的话  斯坦顿先生不见任何人
doesn't see anyone without an appointment.
好吧  早上好  艾金先生
Well, good morning, Mr. Aiken.
早上好
Morning.
我也许能给点帮助
Perhaps I can be of some assistance.
你能给
If you can arrange an
我和秘书长安排个预约吗
appointment for me with the secretary, you can.
不走运  他最近非常忙
Unfortunately he's quite busy right now,
要不你先跟我说几句吧
but perhaps you'd care to have a word with me instead.
请
Please.
我的委托人情况不太好
My client is unwell.
我也听说了  女人的诅咒
So I hear. Touch of the woman's curse.
我要确保她在几天之后
I'm sure she'll be well
可以正常出庭
enough to continue her trial in a few days.
她已经被单独囚禁了一个多月了
She's been in solitary confinement for over a month.
一个多星期都没进食
She hasn't eaten in over a week.
是她拒绝进食
She's refusing to eat.
所有的囚犯每天都提供伙食
All the prisoners are fed daily.
软面包和腌肉
Soft bread and salted meat.
除非她能得到适当的饮食和一些新鲜空气
Unless she has a proper meal and some fresh air,
否则我不能保证她能正常出庭
I can't guarantee she'll be fit for trial.
其中一个共犯拒绝黑人看守
One of the conspirators refuses to be guarded by a Negro,
而另一个坚持只吃他妈做的饭
and the other insists on only eating his mother's cooking.
我们不可能每个人都要满足
We can't accommodate every whim.
算了吧   我只是在请求你们
Come now. I am merely asking
不要把她当成野蛮人那样对待
for you to stop treating her like a savage.
你竟敢指责我们野蛮
How dare you accuse us of savagery?
你难道忘记了反叛者是如何对待我们的
Have you forgotten how our own were treated by the rebels?
当然没有
Of course not.
但是玛丽・萨拉特现在病得很重
But Mary Surratt is in serious decline.
如果再这么下去
If this treatment of her continues,
她早晚会垮掉
she will not be sound of mind.
而我相信这是政府想要避免的
And I trust that is something the government wishes to avoid.
那我想想办法  尽量照顾各方利益
I may have a way to serve all interests.
这事别跟别人说   明白了吗
I'll deny ever telling you this. Understood?
神父
Father.
律师
Counselor.
阳光真好
Feel that sun.
我是不是该向你道谢
Do I have you to thank for this?
谢谢
Well, thank you.
但愿你能有个好胃口
Well, if I could just get you to start eating.
一  一
Left. Left.
一  二  一
Left, right, left.
立定
Company halt.
玛丽  有些事我必须问清楚
Mary, there's something I need to ask you.
年轻人  你总是这么多问题
I've never seen you at a loss for words, young man.
你知道你儿子藏在哪里吗
Do you know where your son is hiding?
约翰尼
Johnny?
当然不知道
Of course not.
政府认为你知道
Government believes you do.
你相信吗
What do you believe?
我认为你还有很多事情没告诉我
I believe you know more than you're willing to tell me.
你有没有比你自己
Uh, have you ever cared for something
更加关心的事
greater than yourself?
我花费将近四年时间
I've spent these last four years
为比我更加重要的事而奋斗
fighting for something greater than myself,
所以不必...
so don't...
那么我们是同一种人
Then we are the same.
玛丽  你必须要告诉我们你的儿子在哪
Mary, you have to tell us where your son is.
你们
Us?
我必须得告诉"你们"
I have to tell "Us"?
你到底是站在哪边
Whose side are you on?
我在努力帮你辩护
I'm trying to defend you.
那就建议我为了自己而出卖儿子吗
By suggesting I trade my son for myself?
你是在努力保护你自己  艾金先生
You're trying to save you, Mr. Aiken.
我也很想告诉你  你需要的东西  真的
I wish I could give you what you need. I truly do.
但你如果想  还是换换别的法子吧
But if you want out, you'll have to find another way.
我要去散步
I'm gonna take a walk.
外面真好
It's so nice out.
要跟我一起来吗
Do you care to walk with me?
所以我们被困在这些浅壕里
So we're stuck in these shallow trenches.
四面被围
We're surrounded on all sides.
没人知道该干什么  该说什么
Nobody knows what to do. Nobody knows what to say.
我们一动不动  呆若木鸡
We're frozen, completely petrified.
然后就在附近某个山头
And then from somewhere up on the hill,
我们听到了大量南方反叛军的声音
we hear this loud booming Southern voice.
这时反叛军官大声喊道
It's the rebel general.
"你们这帮家伙最好开始祈祷吧"
He yells, "Y'all boys better say your prayers,
"因为你们才一百人  而我们是四倍于你"
because there are 400 of us and only 100 of you."
贝克  你停下别说了
You can stop right there, Baker.
然后这个疯狂的男人  站了起来
And so then this madman, he stands up,
他大声回答道
and he yells back to him, and he says...
"见鬼  我们连一百人都没有"
he says, "Hundred? Heck, we've got less than that.
"但是我们绝不投降  你们来吧"
But we don't surrender, so come and get us."
同时
And with that,
他脱下了裤子  用屁股朝向敌军
he pulls down his pants and bares his arse.
你不会的
You didn't.
-当然不会  -什么
- I didn't. - What?
我认为弗雷德是个不会投降的人
It doesn't seem as though Fred ever intends to surrender.
不过现在看来他已经学会投降了
Ah, it appears he already has.
她四十岁  美丽  端庄
She's fair, fit and 40.
萨拉特夫人是名天主教徒
Is it true Mrs. Surratt is a Catholic,
而且从头到脚穿着黑色的衣服  是真的吗
wears black from head to toe?
我听说她只要遇到联邦军人
I hear she spits in the
就会向士兵脸上吐痰
faces of every Union soldier she encounters.
她还带着一条
Apparently she wears a necklace made
用联邦士兵骨头制成的项链
from the bone of a Union soldier.
说真的  弗雷德  你真觉得她没罪吗
Seriously, Fred, do you honestly doubt she's guilty?
好吧  谁想要来跳支舞
So, okay, who would like to dance?
-好的  -好的  不错
- Yes. - Yes. Good.
这曲子?
Dance?
都要让人睡着了
It's more like a wake.
为了配合这曲子
I suppose I should have
我该学学萨拉特夫人的穿着
dressed more like Mrs. Surratt.
弗雷德  你在干什么
Fred, what are you doing?
我在忍受贝克的琴声
I'm enduring the pain of having to listen to Baker.
你知道我说是什么意思
You know what I mean.
如果她被判有罪
If she's found guilty,
他们就会说你玩忽职守
they'll say you weren't up to the task.
即使万一你胜利了
And God forbid you prevail.
他们也会把你跟她同归于卖国贼
They'll think you just as much a traitor as she.
贝克  来个开心点的曲子怎么样
Baker, how 'bout something a little happier?
-开心点的  -是的
- Little happier? - Yeah.
好的  弗雷德要求开心一点的
All right, Fred. Happier, he wants.
威廉说的对
William's right, you know.
无论选哪条路  你都不会获胜
Either outcome, you cannot prevail.
萨拉
Sarah.
到底是玛丽・萨拉特哪方面如此吸引你
What is it about Mary Surratt you find so compelling?
那些人都是些卑鄙的罪犯  弗雷德
These are criminal, despicable people, Fred.
他们都是同一类人
They're... they're the same sort of people
你在冒着生命危险来抗衡
you risked your life fighting against,
而她却是杀死总统的帮凶
and she helped kill your commander in chief.
我不知道她犯了什么罪
I don't know what she's guilty of.
那我能再问你一件事吗
May I ask you one more thing?
萨拉  是什么
What is it, Sarah?
上尉还记得怎么跳舞吗
Does the captain remember how to dance?
当然
Of course.
人们不会忘记你曾为这个国家而战斗
Few people will forget what side you fought on.
相信我  就是有些孤独
Trust me. It can be lonely.
我只用心是在做一名律师的本分工作
I'm just upholding my oath as an attorney
这是你曾对我的要求
and doing my job. It's what you asked.
也是你告诉我该做的
It's what you told me to do.
引用我的话来反驳我
This habit of quoting me back to me
真让人恼火
could become most irritating.
你有你母亲的说服力
You have your mother's
还继承了你父亲的臭毛病
convictions and your father's annoying habits.
"弗雷迪  既然玛丽・萨拉特享有辩护的权利"
Well, "Mary Surratt is entitled to a defense, Freddie,
"那么我就该为她辩护"
so I shall defend her."
如果他们想要约翰・萨拉特
If they want John Surratt,
那就应该把他送上法庭
then you should serve him up on a platter.
我的意思不是指他本人  而是他的罪行
I... I don't mean, uh, physically. I mean in spirit.
你要向陪审团证明是他的责任
You have to prove to the Commission
而不是萨拉特夫人
that he is responsible, not her.
我想她应该不会同意这样做
She's not gonna like that.
劳埃德先生  你是玛丽・萨拉特的一名租户  是吗
Mr. Lloyd, you are a tenant of Mary Surratt, are you not?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我租了她的一块地开家酒馆
I run a tavern some 10 miles from the city
离市区10英里远
on a property she owns.
在林肯遇刺的当天下午
And on the afternoon that President Lincoln was assassinated,
玛丽・萨拉特去找你了吗
did Mary Surratt pay you a visit?
是的  在路易斯・怀克曼的陪同下
Yes, sir, in the company of Louis Weichmann.
她给了你一个包裹  有没有
And she brought you a package, did she not?
是的  没错  先生
Yes, sir. That's correct, sir.
小包裹  用报纸包着的
Small package wrapped in newspaper.
包裹从哪里来的  她告诉你了吗
Did she tell you where the package came from?
约翰・威尔科斯・布思那里来的
Said it came from John Wilkes Booth.
约翰・威尔科斯・布思
John Wilkes Booth!
她给你的包裹里到底是什么
And what exactly did she give you?
反对
Objection.
被告根本不清楚里面是什么东西
There's no way the defendant could have known what was inside.
他只是证明了那东西被报纸包着
He just testified the package was wrapped.
反对无效
Overruled.
证人继续回答问题
Witness will answer the question.
劳埃德  那个包裹里是什么东西
Mr. Lloyd, what was inside the package?
是望远镜  先生
Field glasses, sir.
望远镜
Field glasses?
这种望远镜吗
Field glasses like these?
没错
Exactly.
上面刻着"J.W.B"
With the initials "J.W.B." Inscribed on them.
那她跟你交代了什么
Did she give you any instructions?
什么
Sir?
她对你的交代  劳埃德先生
Instructions, Mr. Lloyd?
那个会影响这次审判走向的交代
Instructions which may affect this trial?
是的  先生
Oh. Yes, sir.
她跟我交代
Ahem. She told me,
"劳埃德  把那些枪准备好"
"Lloyd, get those shootin' irons ready.
"今晚会有人来取走它们"
There will be parties here tonight who will call for them."
你个骗子
You liar!
肃静
Order!
-他是个骗子  -肃静
- He's a liar! - Order!
-这是骗人的  -肃静
- It's a lie. - Order!
请你克制一下  女士
Control yourself, madam.
大吵大闹  只会加重别人对你的偏见
Such outbursts will only prejudice your case.
主啊
Oh, Lord.
我就是不明白
I just don't see how I could
对我怎么还能更加偏见  先生
possibly further prejudice this case, sir.
律师  约束下你的委托人
Counselor, you will control your client.
上将
General.
枪
Shooting irons!
Shooting irons.
她还说了什么
And to what was she referring?
是军用步枪  先生
Army rifles, sir,
藏在餐厅顶子上的栅栏里
hidden in the joist above the dining room.
还有什么
And what else did she tell you?
她还让我去准备两瓶威士忌
She said I was to get two bottles of whiskey ready, too.
你刚所说的内容
And were these things called for,
都是被告交代你去做的吗
as per the defendant's instructions?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
然后半夜的时候  先生
About midnight, sir,
就是刺杀行动当晚
the night of the assassination,
两个骑马的人来找我
by two men on horses, one...
一个认识
I'd seen before.
另一个不认识
T'other was a stranger to me.
我认为他们就是
I brought the items,
萨拉特夫人交代拿货的人
thinking these were the parties
所以就把东西交给他们
Mrs. Surratt meant.
那两个骑马的立刻就走了
Two of 'em rode off so fast,
一溜烟就奔出去两英里
they could have outrun Creation and give it two-mile a start.
换你提问
Your witness.
我不会...
I did not...
劳埃德先生
Mr. Lloyd.
劳埃德先生  你刚刚证实
Mr. Lloyd, you just testified
那天下午路易斯・怀克曼
that Louis Weichmann accompanied
一直陪着被告
the defendant that afternoon.
是的
Right.
那么就是说
So then I can correctly assume
他也能证明
that he would also testify
萨拉特夫人对你的交代
to having heard her instructions to you.
不会
No.
她把我叫到远处的柴堆  跟我说的
She took me out by the woodpile out of earshot.
那么你是说没人能听到这段谈话
So you're saying that nobody heard this conversation,
除了你和她
just you and her.
就是这样  先生
Way it happened, sir.
当然
Of course it is.
你什么时候听说林肯总统遇刺的
When did you learn of President Lincoln's assassination?
谁能忘记
Well, who can forget when they heard?
第二天早晨  科廷厄姆上尉告诉我的
The next morning, a Captain Cottingham told me.
他正在搜查刺客
He was searching for the assassins.
你当时感到非常不安吧
No doubt, you were most upset.
确实
Indeed.
所以我灌了一大口酒
I got myself right smart in liquor.
是啊  你大多数时间都醉醺醺的
Yes, you're... you're right smart in liquor most days,
-不是吗  劳埃德  -反对
- aren't you, Mr. Lloyd? - Objection.
事实上我听说你最好的顾客就是你自己
In fact, I hear that you're your own best customer.
反对
Objection.
反对有效
Sustained.
这个科廷厄姆上尉
This Captain Cottingham,
有没有问你任何有关刺客的情况
did he ask you anything in reference to the assassins?
他问我有没有什么人经过
He asked if any parties had passed through.
我就告诉他那两个我认识的
Naturally I told him about the two I knew.
事实上  你并没有
Actually, you did not.
根据这份目击者证词
According to this witness report,
你整整两天都保持缄默
you said nothing for two days.
我只是害怕了
I was frightened is all.
我担心刺客会冲着我来
I feared the assassins might come for me.
也有可能  你担心当局会认为
Perhaps, though, you were afraid that the authorities
你是同谋
might consider you an accessory.
是萨拉特一家
Well, it was through the
让我陷入了这种局面
Surratts that I got myself in such difficulty.
萨拉特一家
The Surratts.
更确切地说  是约翰・萨拉特吗
Don't you mean John Surratt, to be more precise?
最初是不是他
Wasn't it he who brought the shooting irons
将枪带去你的酒馆的
to your tavern door in the first place?
是的
Yeah.
他是当着你的面把枪藏起来的吗
And he showed you where to hide them?
我并不想的
I didn't want to.
你是说他要求你  逼迫你
So you're saying that he asked you,
去做你本不想做的事
forced you to do so against your will.
是的
Yes.
所以他带着枪去了你那
So he brought them to you,
当着你的面藏了起来
he showed you where to hide them,
又逼迫你违背自己的意愿去藏枪
and he forced you to hide them against your will?
是这样的  就是这样的
That's right. Yes, exactly.
如果约翰・萨拉特有能力
If John Surratt was capable
置劳埃德先生  路易斯・怀克曼
of putting Mr. Lloyd, Louis Weichmann
和其他人于险境
and Lord knows how many others at risk,
谁说他不会对自己的母亲也做一样的事呢
who's to say he didn't do the same to his mother?
-反对  -停下来
- Objection. - Stop this!
长官  看起来...
Sir, it seems the...
立刻停止  艾金先生
Stop it right now, Mr. Aiken.
-看起来唯一...-反对
- It seems the only thing... - Objection.
反对  上将
General, objection.
也许玛丽・萨拉特唯一的罪过
That Mary Surratt might be guilty of
就是生了她的儿子约翰
is having given birth to her son John.
你怎么敢这么说
How dare you?
反对有效  到此为止  艾金先生
Objection sustained. That will be all, Mr. Aiken.
只是确认一下  劳埃德先生
Just to be clear, Mr. Lloyd,
在暗杀前几小时
it was the defendant, Mary Surratt,
给你双筒望远镜并交代
who just hours before the assassination
准备步枪和两瓶威士忌的
brought you field glasses
就是被告
and instructed you to prepare rifles
也就是玛丽・萨拉特  是吗
and two bottles of whiskey?
是的
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
亨特上将
General Hunter,
委员们
members of the Commission,
控方停止对玛丽・萨拉特的辩论
the government rests its case against Mary Surratt.
劳埃德先生  你可以退席了
That'll be all, Mr. Lloyd. You may step down.
他们给你什么让你扯谎  劳埃德先生
What did they promise you to say that, Mr. Lloyd?
律师  我警告你
Counselor, I'm warning you.
估计一箱威士忌也就够了
Bet a case of whiskey's all it took.
闭嘴  不然我就揍扁你  小子
You best hush up. I'll put you in the ground, boy.
艾金先生  坐下来  长官
Mr. Aiken, you will sit down, sir.
让他闭嘴
You shut him up.
坐下来  长官
Sit down, sir.
现在
Now...
休庭
we will adjourn.
重新开庭的时候
When we resume,
辩方可以传唤第一位证人
the defense may call its first witness.
一  一
Left. Left.
抱歉  先生们
Excuse me, sirs.
你是科廷厄姆上尉吗
Uh, Captain Cottingham?
是的
Yes.
能借一步说话吗
Can I have a word with you, please?
长官
Sir.
你是否询问过约翰・劳埃德
And did you interview John Lloyd,
那个在萨拉特女士土地上开酒馆的人呢
the man who runs the tavern on Mrs. Surratt's property?
是的  就在刺杀发生之后
Yes, right after the assassination.
他是否告诉你萨拉特女士
And did he tell you that Mrs. Surratt
要求步枪和威士忌呢
asked for rifles and whiskey?
是的  劳埃德说萨拉特女士要求他准备这些东西
Yes. Lloyd said Mrs. Surratt asked him to do all those things.
你说什么
Uh, excuse me?
我们不是昨天才谈过吗
Did we not talk just yesterday?
是的
We did.
你不是说过
And did you not say
萨拉特女士从未
that Mrs. Surratt never
要求过约翰・劳埃德准备威士忌和步枪吗
asked for whiskey or rifles of John Lloyd?
我并未否认
I do not deny that.
但你现在发誓说
And now you're swearing,
你曾跟我说的一切都是谎言
under oath, that what you told me then was a lie.
是的  我骗你是因为
Yes. I lied to you 'cause
我觉得你无权过问
I thought you had no business to ask me.
无权过问  我
No business? I...
你是我的证人
You're my witness.
我难道不该知道真相吗
Should I not expect the truth?
我站在这里说  我骗了你
I state here that I did lie to you,
但在誓约之下  现在我说的是实话
but under oath, now I'm telling the truth.
霍特先生  你要对证人提问吗
Mr. Holt, do you wish to question the witness?
不  我相信我们所听到的已经足够了
Uh, no. I believe what we've heard is more than sufficient.
上尉  你可以退席了
Captain, you may step down.
众所周知  今晚政府
As you know, tonight marks
要为我们的军队举办庆典
Washington's celebration honoring our troops,
因此休庭
so we will adjourn.
这还不够  是吗  霍特先生
It's not enough, is it, Mr. Holt?
你定下了规则   你指定了法官
It's not enough that you, uh... you set the rules.
这还不够吗
You... You pick the judges.
现在你又策反了我的证人
Now you have to turn my witness as well.
被告律师  自重
Counselor, control yourself.
控方也请自重
Control the prosecution.
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken.
所有我想要找的证人
Every witness I wish to call has
不是被关进了监狱就是被此威胁
either been turned by jail or the threat of it.
够了
That's enough!
控方则是为所欲为  丝毫没有限制
There is no limit to how far the prosecution is willing to go!
被告律师退席  否则视作藐视公堂
Stand down, counselor, or I will hold you in contempt.
你的行为最好更得体一点
You had better comport yourself in a more appropriate manner,
不然你会和他们一样被关起来的
or you will find yourself incarcerated with the others.
晚上好
Good evening.
晚上好  道格拉斯
Good evening, Douglas.
-夫人  -晚上好
- Ma'am. - Good evening.
艾金先生  能借一步说话吗
Mr. Aiken, may I have a word with you?
当然  失陪一下
Of course. Would you excuse me?
他第一天上班
His first day on the job.
基于行为不当
弗雷德里克・A・艾金的会员身份即刻被取消
我很抱歉  艾金先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Aiken.
这没什么  道格拉斯  不是你的错
It's all right, Douglas. It's not your fault.
弗雷德里克
Frederick!
尼克  能陪萨拉上楼吗
Uh, Nick, would you escort Sarah upstairs for me, please?
当然  不过
Sure, but, uh...
-一切都还好吗  -一切都好
- Is everything all right? - Everything's fine.
来吧  萨拉
Come on, Sarah.
即使只有一条好腿  我也跳得比他好
Even with one good leg, I can still outdance him.
改天吧  尼克
Another night, Nick.
萨拉
Sarah.
萨拉  你去哪
Sarah, where are you going?
"行为不当"
"Conduct unbecoming."
关于舞会  我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry about the party.
你以为我在乎什么舞会吗
You think I care about the party?
拜托了  一切都会好起来的  我保证
Please. Everything will be all right. I promise you.
你和那个女人一样
You are just like that woman,
都准备为了毫无意义的事奔赴刑场
ready to go to the gallows for the most pointless cause.
在你这么做的时候把所有人都抛下了
People do get left behind when you do that.
我没办法无视在法庭发生的一切
I can't ignore what's going on in that courtroom.
但你可以无视我  无视我们
But you can ignore me, us?
我没这么说  拜托  我必须这么做
I didn't say that. Please, I have to do this.
是吗
Do you?
你全部心思都在这件危险的事上
I find your devotion to this frightening.
我等了这么长时间
I waited such a long time for you.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我知道  但是我现在回来了
I know. But I'm back now.
你没回来
No, you're not.
我  我...
I am. I... ple...
萨拉  拜托了  你能不能就
Sarah, please, will you just...
我们得  我们得谈谈
We have to... we have to talk about this.
弗雷德  我爱你  我
Fred, I love you. I...
我希望我能做到  只是  我不能
I wish I could do this. I just... I can't.
我就是没办法
I just can't.
等等  至少让我送你回家
Wait. Let me see you home at least.
等我  好吗
Please wait.
部长先生
Uh, Mr. Secretary.
我得跟你谈谈
I have to speak with you.
艾金先生  这也许不是什么好时机
Mr. Aiken, perhaps this isn't the best time.
发生在玛丽・萨拉特身上事是不能容忍的
What is happening to Mary Surratt is an abomination.
退下  上尉
Stand down, Captain.
没事
It's all right.
能陪斯坦顿夫人进去吗
Would you escort Mrs. Stanton in?
我就来
I'll just be a moment.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
年轻人
Young man...
你的勇气总是令人赞赏
always indebted to you for your courage in the field,
但你必须学会谨言慎行
but you must learn to tread lightly.
谨言慎行
Tread lightly?
我是不会谨言慎行的
I will not tread lightly.
你早就认定了她的命运
You have predetermined her fate.
玛丽・萨拉特的命运完全由委员会决定
Mary Surratt's fate rests entirely with the Commission.
我关心的是保护我们的联邦
My concern is preserving our Union.
如果我自己的权力都无法得到保障
Why did I fight for the Union
又为何要为联邦奋斗呢
if my rights aren't assured?
你来告诉我
You tell me.
巧言辞令可以召集军队  却不能管理国家
Fine words for rallying the troops, not for running a nation.
他们暗杀了总统
They assassinated our president,
必须有人为之责任
and someone must be held accountable.
人民需要这样
The people want that.
你想要的是约翰・萨拉特  你根本不想要玛丽
It's John Surratt you want. You don't even want Mary.
有一个我就满足了
I'll settle for either one.
如果你不介意的话  我太太在等我
If you'll excuse me, my wife is waiting.
蓝天鹅
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken.
我能进来吗
May I come in?
-很晚了  -我知道
- It's late. - I know.
我需要你去作证
I need you to testify.
很好
Very well.
我会告诉他们我妈是无辜的
I'll tell them my mother's innocent.
我需要你告诉他们你哥哥有罪
I need you to tell them that your brother is not.
我不会这么做的
I won't do it.
如果不这么做  你知道她会怎么样吗
You know what'll happen to her if you don't?
安娜
Anna...
你哥哥目前并不需要被拯救
Your brother does not need to be saved right now.
但你母亲需要
Your mother does.
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken,
你还想要传唤别的证人吗
are there any other witnesses you wish to call?
是的
Uh, yes.
辩方
The... The defense
想要传唤安娜・萨拉特小姐
would like to call Miss Anna Surratt.
亨特上将  这是要
General Hunter, what is...
请将右手放在圣经上
Place your right hand on this Bible.
我妈在哪
Where's my mother?
安娜  她就在这
Anna, she's just right here,
在这些人后面
behind these men.
为什么不让我看到她
Why won't they let me see her?
我不知道
I don't know.
萨拉特小姐  请
Please, Miss Surratt.
你是否发誓说出真相  毫无保留
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth
不加掩饰的真相  以此让上帝帮助你?
and nothing but the truth, so help you, God?
安娜小姐
Miss Anna.
我发誓
I do.
不会有事的
It'll be all right.
萨拉特小姐  你能否告诉我们
Miss Surratt, can you tell us
你哥哥是什么时候认识
when your brother first became acquainted
约翰・威尔科斯・布思的
with John Wilkes Booth?
萨拉特小姐  回答问题
Miss Surratt, you will answer the question.
我想我哥是一月份认识他的
I believe my brother met him January last.
暗杀前三个月
Three months before the assassination.
能和这么有名的演员作朋友
He must have been mighty
他一定很高兴
pleased to have befriended such a famous actor.
这你得问他了
You'll have to ask him.
我们都很希望能问他
Well, I'm sure we'd all like to ask him.
你哥哥很自豪地宣称
Your brother proudly called
自己是布思的朋友  是吗
himself a friend of Booth's, did he not?
艾金先生  你在做什么
Mr. Aiken, what are you doing?
妈
Mother!
萨拉特小姐  萨拉特小姐
Miss Surratt. Miss Surratt, please.
萨拉特小姐
Miss Surratt.
我从未
I never...
问过我哥哥和布思的关系怎么样
asked what my brother's relationship was to Booth.
是约翰首先
It was at John's invitation
邀请他去你家的  是吗
that he first came to your home, was it not?
是的
Yes.
这张布思的照片是你的吗
Does this picture of Booth belong to you?
有天我在画廊发现了这张照片
I found it in a gallery one day,
我就买了下来
and I bought it.
自己的朋友如此受重视
Your brother must have been
你哥哥一定很高兴
pleased that you held his friend in such high regard.
-不是的  -不是
- No. - No?
他叫我把照片撕了扔掉
No. He told me to tear it up and throw it away.
为什么
Why?
为什么你哥哥要让你
Why did your brother tell you to destroy
毁了他朋友  布思的照片呢
a photograph of his friend, Booth?
别这样  艾金先生
No, Mr. Aiken!
-请回答  -我求你了
- Please. - I beg of you.
-请回答  -肃静
- Please. - Order!
萨拉特小姐  请回答
Miss Surratt, please.
回答我的问题
Answer my question.
我觉得他是想保护我们
I suppose he was trying to protect us.
他想要保护你和你母亲?
He was trying to protect you and your mother?
是的
Yes.
为什么他需要保护他的家庭
Why would he need to protect his family?
安娜  你得作出选择
Anna, you have to choose.
我觉得
I suppose...
他和布思在计划什么
he and Booth were planning something.
他在计划什么
He was planning something.
你知道是什么吗
Did you know what?
当然不知道
Of course not.
你最后一次见到你哥哥是什么时候
When did you last see your brother?
他四月初就走了
He left at the beginning of April.
就在暗杀的前几天
Days before the assassination.
他有没有告诉你他要去哪
Did he tell you where he was going
或者他在计划什么吗
or what he might be planning?
他只是说他必须离开
He only said he had to leave.
你和母亲有试图阻止他吗
And did you or your mother try to stop him?
是的
Yes.
但我们阻止不了
But we couldn't.
你们怎么能阻止的了呢  他很愤怒
How could you? He was angry.
他对战争满心沮丧
He was frustrated with the war.
他痛恨联邦
He hated the Union.
他愿意做任何事来帮助布思
He would have done anything in his power,
即使让他的家庭陷入危险
even risk his own family to aid Booth in his cause.
但是  萨拉特小姐
But, Miss Surratt, did
你母亲有没有和约翰・威尔科斯・布思合谋呢
your mother conspire with John Wilkes Booth?
绝对没有
Absolutely not.
谢谢
Thank you.
没有更多问题了
There are no more questions.
亨特上将  政府能够理解
General Hunter, the government understands
萨拉特小姐愿意做任何事
why Miss Surratt would be moved
来掩盖她母亲的罪行
to the most extraordinary lengths to conceal her mother's guilt,
包括归罪于她的亲哥哥
including incriminating her own brother.
我妈是无辜的
My mother is innocent.
萨拉特小姐  你可以离开了
Miss Surratt, you are dismissed.
政府认为不再有必要扣留你
The government no longer deems it necessary to hold you.
你可以走了
You are free to leave.
我只想见见我妈
I just want to see my mother.
求你了  对不起  妈
Please. I'm sorry, mother.
对不起
I'm sorry.
求你了  求你了  让我见见她
Please. Please, let me see her.
长官  辩方请求委员会
Sir, the defense would push for the Commission
让一位母亲见见她的女儿
to show some compassion and allow a mother
只要一会儿就行
to see her daughter for a brief moment only.
明天早上再开庭
We will reconvene in the morning.
弗雷德里克  是我
Frederick, it's me.
安娜
Anna.
你在这干吗
What are you doing here?
你从没问过为什么我会有布思的照片
You never asked why I had Booth's photo.
撕了它  把它扔掉
Tear that up and throw it away.
他会让我们都陷入麻烦的
That man is gonna get us all in trouble,
甚至更糟
if not worse.
我应该把它扔掉
I should have thrown it away,
但是我没有
but I didn't.
你迷恋上布思了
So you were infatuated with Booth.
我发誓我不知道他会做什么
I swear I didn't know what he was capable of.
我相信你  但是你哥哥知道
I believe you. But your brother did.
没有我哥哥你能救我妈吗
Can you save my mother without him?
能吗  弗雷德里克
Can you, Frederick?
大概不行
Probably not.
沃尔特神父
Father Walter!
神父
Father?
能失陪一下吗
Will you excuse us for a minute?
律师
Counselor.
我现在就要见约翰・萨拉特
I need to see John Surratt right away.
安娜・萨拉特让我来的
Anna Surratt sent me.
就像我告诉萨拉特小姐的一样
Well, as I told Miss Surratt,
我只能传递消息
I can only pass along a message.
他在哪
Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
只有教堂的人
Only that some in the
能给他提供避难所
church have chosen to provide him sanctuary.
看来他们的选择并没有让你陷入麻烦
You don't seem troubled by their choice.
你因为这个就送他去绞刑架吗
You prefer he be crucified by this mob?
可他也不是什么好人
John is hardly the Prince of Peace.
他因为谋杀与叛国罪正被通缉
He's wanted for murder and treason.
窝藏罪犯不仅不道德  神父  而且非法
Harboring him is not only immoral, Father, it's illegal.
我的法在这儿  律师  我只听上帝的
Our laws are written here, counselor, our allegiance to God.
恕我直言  神父
You forgive me, Father,
你讲的都是废话
but that's a bunch of cock and bull.
人们对圣经的看法各有不同
Bible bears as many interpretations as anything else.
你有什么口信要我转达的
Is there a message you wish me to pass along?
我的案子明天结案
My case summary is tomorrow,
所以你告诉约翰・萨拉特  除非他自首
so you tell John Surratt that unless he surrenders himself,
否则他母亲将因为他犯的罪而受惩罚
his mother will most likely be punished for his crimes.
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken.
律师也好  士兵也好
For the lawyer as well as the soldier,
都有一种急迫的使命感
there is an equally imperative command.
我们有义务去为无辜者伸张正义
That duty is to shelter from injustice the innocent,
去保护弱者反抗压迫
to protect the weak from oppression
必要时
and, when necessity demands,
为那些冤民鼓舞打气
to rally to the defense of those being wronged.
在经历了我国历史上
After the most thorough
最完整的一次调查之后
investigation in our nation's history,
政府对玛丽・萨拉特的指控
the government's entire case against Mary Surratt
基于三点
rests on three acts...
一  她与布思的相识
one, her acquaintance with Booth,
二  她对劳埃德作的指示
two, her alleged instructions to Lloyd,
三  否认与佩恩相识
and, three, her nonrecognition of Payne.
就是这三点构成了
It is these three acts that constitute the sum total
玛丽・萨拉特
of Mary Surratt's part
参与叛国与谋杀的罪状
in this traitorous and murderous conspiracy.
他们认为自己是无辜的
By themselves, they constitute no crime.
你和我也许做过同样的事情
Any one of you or I might have done the same,
但是政府坚持认为她用心险恶
but the government insists she did them with evil intent,
大部分基于约翰・劳埃德与
largely based on the testimony of two men,
路易斯・怀克曼的证词
John Lloyd and Louis Weichmann.
到现在为止  最好的可能是
Yet, at best, the actions
这些人出尔反尔
of these men undermine their credibility,
最坏的可能是  他们干了见不得人的勾当
and, at worst, they have done the unspeakable...
他们为了洗脱罪名
they have gained their freedom
而去撒谎诬陷别人
by falsely accusing another of their crime.
我们相信玛丽・萨拉特今天在这里
There can be no doubt as to the principal and real reason
有她自己真正的原因
that Mary Surratt is here today.
就是她的儿子  约翰・萨拉特
It's because of her son, John Surratt.
是他请布思去他家的  不是她
He invited Booth into her home. She did not.
是他把枪和弹药藏在劳埃德的酒馆里
And he hid rifles and ammunition in Lloyd's Tavern.
不是她
She did not.
如果约翰・萨拉特是个共犯
If John Surratt was part of this conspiracy,
我祈求上帝
I pray to God that he receives
用各种方法惩罚他
every punishment known to man,
而如果他母亲因为不足的证据
but if his mother can be convicted
被判有罪的话
on such insufficient evidence,
你们会有报应的
I tell you none of you are safe.
各位庭审法官们
Members of the Commission,
请还玛丽・萨拉特一个公道
do not permit this injustice to Mary Surratt
而不是出于报复而牺牲我们的天赋人权
by sacrificing our sacred rights out of revenge.
为了捍卫它们而倒下的人已经太多了
Too many of us have laid down our lives to preserve them.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我们敬爱的总统被一颗子弹就夺走了生命
One bullet may have killed our beloved president.
一颗子弹  但不是一个人干的
One bullet, but not one man.
过来坐
Sit with me.
有什么消息吗
Is there any word?
没有  他们还在审议
No. They're still deliberating.
我是说我儿子
I mean about my son.
我把他管得太紧了
I held him too close.
我不想约翰变成他父亲那样
I didn't want John turning out like his father,
所以我看着他
so I kept him near.
战争爆发时  他想参军
And when the war broke out, he wanted to enlist,
我没让他去
but I wouldn't let him.
我儿子只想冲破牢笼
My son just needed to break free...
做一回自己
be his own man.
就用了这样的方式
And this is the way he did it.
都赞成吗
All those in favor?
赞成
Aye.
好  我们都同意了
Well, then, we are all agreed
被判死刑的犯人是
on the penalty of death for the prisoners
赫罗尔德・阿泽特和佩恩
Herold, Atzerodt and Payne.
那女人呢
What about the woman?
关于玛丽・萨拉特
Regarding Mary Surratt,
都赞成吗  先生们
all those in favor, gentlemen?
不行
No.
该死
Damn it!
不行
No.
她必须要接受惩罚
No, she must be punished to the full extent.
我要这些人立刻消声灭迹
I want these people buried and forgotten.
大多数人倾向于一个比较宽容的判决
The majority prefer a more merciful sentence,
基于她年龄  性别的无期徒刑
life in prison on account of her age, gender.
艾金先生很能干
I give Mr. Aiken credit.
他知道怎么利用她女儿
He knew just how to use the daughter.
没错
It seems so.
你向委员会传达了我的意思了吗
You made my sentiments known to the Commission?
判决已经定了
Their minds are made.
那我们改变他们
Then let us change them.
在对证据的反复考量之后
After mature consideration of the evidence,
本委员会判你  玛丽・E・苏拉特
Commission finds you, Mary E. Surratt,
有罪
Guilty...
企图谋杀亚伯拉罕・林肯总统
Guilty of conspiring to kill and murder
之罪名成立
President Abraham Lincoln,
企图谋杀美国副总统安德鲁・约翰逊
Guilty of conspiring to kill and murder
之罪名成立
andrew Johnson, vice president of the United States,
企图谋杀美国国务卿威廉・H・苏厄德
Guilty of conspiring to kill and murder
之罪名成立
William H. Seward, secretary of State.
本委员会由此宣判你
The Commission does therefore sentence you
处以绞刑
to be hanged by the neck until you be dead.
玛丽・萨拉特死期已到
Mary Surratt to meet her doom!
四名刺客午时处死
Four assassins die tomorrow at noon!
给你  先生
Here you go, sir.
玛丽・萨拉特死期已到
Mary Surratt to meet her doom!
四名刺客午时处死
Four assassins die tomorrow at noon!
萨拉特先生  给  先生
Mr. Surratt. Here, sir.
一定还有办法救她
There must be something we can do.
你有三个选择
You have three options:
请求总统暂缓行刑
Petition the president for a stay of execution...
但是  他不会那么做
but, uh, he won't do that,
因为如果他做了
because if he did,
人们会认为 他也是个共犯
people would think he was part of the conspiracy.
第二  申请个书面人身保护令
Uh, two, apply for a writ of habeas corpus
带她去民事法庭
to retry her in a civilian court,
但是没有哪个法官愿意得罪斯坦顿
but no judge would oppose Stanton
或者陆军部的人
or the might of the War Department.
还有  第三  约翰・萨拉特
Uh, and, three, John Surratt
在明天中午之前自首
shows himself before noon tomorrow.
你要出差吗
Are you going somewhere?
我在巴尔的摩有笔生意
I have business in Baltimore.
什么
What?
你现在可不能走
You... You can't leave now!
都结束了
It's over.
弗雷迪  她不是你的母亲
Freddie, she's not your mother.
如果约翰・萨拉特都不想救他妈
If John Surratt won't give himself up for her,
你为什么要救呢
then why should you?
弗雷迪
Freddie!
弗雷德里克・塞巴斯蒂安・艾金
Frederick Sebastian Aiken,
我们知道你在
we know you're in there!
快开门  快
Open the door now. Come on.
弗雷德  你在啊
Fred... ah, there he is.
如果你还不想隐居  艾金
Well, if it isn't the reclusive Master Aiken.
我们还可以喝一杯
We thought you could use this.
汉密尔顿  你对奥林法官了解多少
Hamilton, how well do you know Judge Olin?
干什么
What are you doing?
你认为他会给我签人身保护令吗
You think he'll give me a writ of habeas corpus?
你不能这样做
You can't pursue a writ.
他们不让我上诉
They won't allow me to appeal this verdict,
那我就申请一个新法庭
so I'm gonna appeal for a new trial.
如果你这样做  是在羞辱斯坦顿
If you do this, you will humiliate Stanton,
然后他会毁了你
and he will destroy you.
让斯坦顿见鬼去吧
The hell with Stanton.
你为什么  为什么坚持帮她
Why do you... Why do you insist on standing by her?
喂喂  根本没有用
Hey. Hey, it makes no sense.
他们那样对她是不对的
What they're doing to her is wrong.
如果那样对待约翰・威尔科斯・布思
If John Wilkes Booth himself was tried in the same manner,
也是不对的
it would still be wrong.
汉密尔顿  她离上绞刑架不到12小时了
Hamilton, she's to hang in less than 12 hours.
奥林法官出城了
Judge Olin's out of town.
他会是我的第一选择
He would have been my first choice.
怀力怎么样
What about Wylie?
也许吧
Maybe Wylie.
他  他一直被认为是个自由思想者
He's, uh- -he's always been known as a Free Thinker.
是啊  这么多年老练世故
Yes. He's been around for ages,
但是他跟林肯交情最深
but he was the closest to Lincoln.
那卡特怎么样
Then what about Carter?
没门儿  刺杀那晚
Not a chance. He was with
他跟斯坦顿在一起
Stanton on the night of the assassination.
再说  他们每周聚一次会餐
Besides, they have dinner together once a week.
那你意思是怀力是我的最佳选择
Then you're saying that Wylie is my best option.
不是  你的最佳选择是别再发疯了
No. Your best option is to stop this nonsense
陪我们喝光这瓶酒
and help us empty this bottle.
最好听他的话
Better listen to the man.
怀力法官吗
Judge Wylie?
我  我需要申请一张人身保护令
I, uh... I need to apply for a writ of habeas corpus.
在这个时候
At this hour of the night?
抱歉  先生  实在等不了了
I'm sorry, sir. It can't wait.
那就要把一个老人吵醒吗
Interrupting an old man's sleep?
我想你走错门了  小伙子
I'd say you're getting off on the wrong foot, son.
是玛丽・萨拉特的案子
It's for Mary Surratt.
重新开庭
A new trial...
一个由她同辈的陪审团组成的民事法庭
in a civil court by a jury of her peers.
那就是你的目的吗  艾金先生
Is that what you want, Mr. Aiken?
是  求您了  法官大人
Yes, please, Your Honor.
所以我们能再次经历一次总统被刺的过程
So we can relive our president's assassination all over again.
那可不是我的本意
That's not my intention.
那你的本意是什么
Then to what intent?
也许结果会不一样吗
Might this not result in exactly the same thing?
也许吧  但是结果
Perhaps, but results
不应该成为评判公义的标尺
should not be our only measure of justice.
你在教训我不懂什么是公义吗
Are you going to lecture me on justice?
不敢  先生
Sorry, sir.
你知道我是被林肯总统亲自任命的
You realize that I was personally appointed by President Lincoln.
是
Yes.
那你还来找我
And yet you still come to me.
恕我直言  法官大人
Forgive me, Your Honor,
我们不是在任何时候都有义务去坚持法理
but are we not obligated to follow the law at all times,
而忽略情理吗
regardless of our emotions?
这个不是你一时冲动吗
And is this not driven by emotions?
难道不是吗
Isn't that what this is all about?
这是为了不冤枉好人
It's about preventing injustice.
我知道人们还是愤愤不平
Now, I know that the people are still angry.
对  没错  我也是
Yes, they are, and so am I.
可我希望  我坚信林肯总统
But I hope, I trust that President Lincoln
任命你是因为你手上握着神圣的宪法
appointed you because you hold the Constitution sacred.
不管你相信玛丽・萨拉特有罪还是无辜的
Whether you believe Mary Surratt is guilty or innocent,
宪法的宗旨就在于
the Constitution was intended...
现在你又要给我上宪法课了
And now you're gonna lecture me on the Constitution.
无论在战时或和平时期
...to protect the rights
他会保护所有公民的所有权利不受侵犯
of all citizens at all times in peace or war.
再过几个小时
And in a matter of hours,
宪法将被践踏  除非你在那上面签字
it will have failed to protect her unless you sign that writ.
你确信她是无辜的吗
You believe she's innocent?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是如果得不到一个公平审判
But if we don't get a proper trial,
我们永远不会知道
we never will.
你不能进去  喂
You can't go in there! Wait!
真抱歉  部长先生  我拦不住他
I'm so sorry, Mr. Secretary. I tried to stop him.
没事
It's all right.
早上好  约瑟夫
Good morning, Joseph.
早上好
Good morning.
看来艾金先生
It appears that Mr. Aiken
要了一张怀力法官签名的保护令
has procured a writ signed by Judge Wylie.
再见
Good day.
等一下  上尉
Before you go, Captain,
告诉我
tell me...
当你第一次听说我们的国务卿
when you first learned that our secretary of State
被搞得焦头烂额
had been butchered to within an inch of his life
他们把一粒子弹
and that they put a bullet
送进了我们总统的脑袋
in the back of our president's head,
让这个城市混乱不堪时
when this city was in chaos,
你难道不希望看到秩序得到恢复
did you not wish to see order restored
正义得到伸张吗
and justice served,
或许你只关心那些
or were you just concerned with
刺客的权利
the rights of the assassins?
你关心的不是正义  而是报复
It's not justice you're after. It's revenge.
我不会出于复仇而如此低声下气
I would never go to such lengths out of vengeance,
但是为了这个国家的生存
but to ensure the survival of this nation,
我会不择手段
I would do anything.
玛丽・萨拉特是有史以来
Mary Surratt was a party to the most
最让人痛心的犯罪党羽
grievous crime in our history.
必要时我们会给她一个迅速
Necessity demands that she be given a swift,
绝对  残酷的判决
sure and harsh sentence.
我一样坚信我们的天赋人权  律师
I, too, hold sacred our rights, counselor,
但是如果我们的国家不在了
but they count not at all
说什么都是屁话
if our nation ceases to exist.
请在中午之前
Please see to it that Mary Surratt
确保玛丽・萨拉特
is delivered to Judge Wylie's courtroom
准时到庭
no later than noon...
再见
sir.
快走  停下
Let's go. Come on. Stay there.
你得再次上庭
You will have to stand trial again,
但是这次是民事法庭
but it will be a civilian trial.
民事法庭没有将军参加吧
And a civilian trial has no generals.
对  没有将军参加
That's correct. No generals.
祝福你  孩子
Bless you, son.
祝福你
Bless you.
妈
Oh, Mama.
安娜
Anna.
应该三架才对
Should only be three.
到点了  夫人
It's time, ma'am.
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
我们需要把她带走
We need to prepare her with the others.
不不  她已经转为重新上庭了
No. No, she is to be transferred to Judge Wylie's court.
我建议让这位小姐保持镇定
I advise sedating the young lady.
-你们别想这么做  -安娜
- You'll do no such thing. - Anna.
根据我的人身保护令  她的案子要重审
I have procured a writ that says she is to get a new trial.
总统刚刚取消了你的保护令
President just suspended your writ.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
她必须要走了
She's to hang with the others.
不
No.
不  弗雷德里克  想想办法啊
No. Frederick, do something.
我
I...
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不  不
Oh, no.
不不不
No. No, no, no, no.
不  妈  别走  妈
No, Mama. No. No, Mama. No.
我永远在你身边
I'll always be with you.
不不不  妈
No! No! Oh, Mama, no!
我爱你  安娜  我爱你
I love you, Anna. I love you.
不
No!
天啊  不
Oh, God, no!
妈
Mama!
拉丁语
战时无法律
In times of war, the law falls silent.
扯淡
It shouldn't.
这个词是最后一位南军上将
Word is the last Confederate general
向联邦军投降时说的
surrendered to Union troops.
和平
Peace.
终于和平了
Peace at last.
我奉命来这里
I am hereby commanded
执行戴维・E・赫罗尔德
to cause David E. Herold,
G・A・阿泽特
G. A. Atzerodt,
刘易斯・佩恩
Lewis Payne
和玛丽・E・苏拉特
and Mary E. Surratt
的死刑
to be executed
根据美国总统
in accordance with the
安德鲁・约翰逊
order of the president of the United States,
的命令
Andrew Johnson.
万能的主保佑你
The Almighty God bless you.
罪犯起立
Stand your prisoners up.
双手反绑
Step them to the noose.
16个月之后
好的  先生  我带你去
Okay, sir. I'll show you where he's at...
不用  我认识路
No, I know the way.
艾金先生
Mr. Aiken.
我没想到你会来
I didn't think you'd come.
不知道我能帮你什么忙
I don't know what help I can be to you.
我已经不当律师了
I've left the law.
我只想谢谢你
I just wanted to thank you
对我妈那么好
for the kindness that you showed my mother.
相信我  艾金先生
Believe me, Mr. Aiken,
我还以为他们不会杀她
I never thought they'd kill her.
沃尔特神父叫我给你这个
Father Walter asked that I give you these.
你母亲的遗物
They were your mother's.
我希望它们能给你安慰
I hope they can be of some comfort to you.
它们是你的了
They belong to you.
你比我更有资格做她的儿子
You were more of a son to her than I ever was.
请开门
Thank you.
一年之后
高级法院毫无争议地规定
公民享有由陪审团旁听的权利
甚至是在战争时期
由北方与南方组成的陪审团
对约翰・萨拉特的裁决争执不下
他最终被无罪释放
弗雷德里克・艾金离开法律界之后
在新开张的华盛顿邮报当上了首个新闻主编